你是要米奇也来吗
Are you gonna... You bringing Micky in?
1993年  马萨诸塞州  洛厄尔
是的  他在这
Yeah, he's here.
应该叫上他  他也该一起来
He should come. He should be here as well.
我们以为米奇只是来回答问题
We thought that Micky is coming to answer the questions.
不  说是让我们俩都上镜
No, they said it was going to be both of us.
我现在正对着摄像机吗
Am I looking right into the camera here?
看着我就行
Just look at me right now.
好吧
All right.
你采访时不看摄像机吗
You're not going to look at the camera with the interviews?
我十二岁那年开始打拳击
I started boxing when I was twelve years old
我当时骗他们说我十八岁了
and I lied and said I was eighteen or whatever it was.
名字啥的都是假的
I had a different name and everything.
我说我没打过架
I mean, I don't have any fights,
其实在我成为职业选手前
I've done a hundred more than that
打过无数次架
before I turned professional.
今天早上你说
This morning you said that...
-我们干嘛拍这个  -再来一次
- Why are we doing this? - One more time.
你想重头来一遍吗  再录一次
You want to go over it all? You want to start again?
他是我弟弟  我把所有本事都教给他了
He's my younger brother. I taught him everything he knows.
我现在还是他的教练  我们风格迥异
I'm still his trainer. I know we've got different styles,
我他妈的喜欢出其不意
I'm fucking squirelly as fuck.
就好像我还没在状态
You know, like, I'm not even there.
苏格・雷就这么说过
That's what Sugar Ray said.
我是他碰过的最狡猾的拳击手
I was the most tricky fighter he'd ever come across.
迪克・埃克伦德对阵苏格・雷・莱纳德
1978年7月18日  马萨诸塞州  波士顿
1978年  在苏格・雷・莱纳德以前
'78, before Sugar Ray Leonard...
我告诉过他  他打不赢我
I told him he couldn't get to me.
他打不赢我
He couldn't get to me.
大家都称我为洛厄尔的骄傲
They called me "The Pride of Lowell."
大家至今都在谈论  尤其是我弟弟
Everybody still talks about it, you know, especially my brother.
他一生都想从事我所做的事
His whole life he wanted to do what I did, you know?
但我们是完全不同的拳击手
But we're very different fighters.
米奇是强击手  他出拳强而有力  要我说
Micky's a heavy hitter. He's thunderous, I'm telling you.
他的左拳威力巨大
Thunderous left punch.
米奇  他简直是自虐
Micky, he takes a punishment.
我不知道他为什么这么做
I don't know why he does it.
我会问他  你没事吧  他在里面奋斗
I'd say "You all right?" He likes getting on the inside.
而我则在场外支持他
I stay on the outside.
根据真实故事改编
别闹了
Come on!
迪奇
Dicky...
别闹了行吗
Would you come on?
别再闹了  你得帮我干完这个
Stop. You've got to help me finish this.
别闹了
Come on!
一如既往地无法预测
Unpredictable as ever!
你不用成为神探哥伦坡就知道朝哪出拳
You don't have to be Columbo to see where this fight is headed!
太棒了
Yeah, bam!
他一拳将米奇・沃德打倒在地
All right, he punched Micky Ward down!
HBO要将我的回归  还有我弟弟下周
HBO's making a movie on me and my comeback
在亚特兰大击败绍尔・麦比的故事拍成电影
and my brother is going to beat Saoul Mamby in Atlanta next week!
洛厄尔的骄傲又回来了
The Pride of Lowell is back!
呱呱
Quacker!
斗士
谁要来点  谁要来点
Who wants some? Who wants some?
算我一份
I want a cut.
怎么样
Doing good?
你们今天好吗
You guys having a good day?
你好吗
How are you?
来啊  你想怎么着  要出什么招
Come on. Come on. What you got? What you got going on?
卢  喂  卢・迪拜勒
Lou! Hey, Lou DiBella!
你们好吗
How are you guys, huh?
我卷土重来了
I'm making my comeback.
马蒂  到这来
Hey, Marty, Marty. Come out here, huh?
HBO要给我拍电影
HBO is making a movie on me!
嗨  美妞
Hey, beautiful.
你喜欢她吗
You got that?
压根不记得她是谁  啥都想不起来
Can't remember who she is. I can't remember shit!
加西亚
Hey! Hey, Garcia!
怎样  你还真不错啊
How are you, nice?
你怎么来的  开车吗
How'd you get here? Drive around?
喂  雷  我爱你  伙计
Hey, Ray. Hey. I love you, Ray.
我就这意思
This is what it's all about.
他搞错时间了吗
He make mistake?
没有  他会来的  我也说了
No, he'll be here. Like I said,
有时他按自己的时间表行事
sometimes he goes on his own schedule,
但他一旦来了  我们会很努力
but when he gets here we work hard.
没人比他更严格地鞭策我了
Nobody pushes me harder than him.
他应该现在训练你的吧
He's supposed to be training you right now, right?
你怎么不去和我姐妹们聊聊
Why don't you just go talk to them, my sisters?
她们会絮絮叨叨让你听烦
They'll talk your ear off.
你得出钱她们才会闭嘴
You gotta pay them to shut up.
他可以讲迪奇是怎么帮他的
He can tell you how Dicky was helping him.
说吧  米奇
Come on, Micky.
好吧
Okay.
我们不知道迪奇在哪
Hey, we don't know where Dicky is.
你知道他在哪
You know where he is.
那个蠢蛋条子在这搞什么
What's that dumb cop doing in there?
姑娘们  迪奇呢
Where's Dicky? Girls?
-我不知道  -你今早见到他了吗
- I don't know. - You see him this morning?
-看到你兄弟了吗  -今早没见到
- Your brother? - Not this morning.
看妈妈  为拍电影还盛装打扮
Look at Mom! All dressed up for the movie, huh?
身材真是火爆
You are smoking hot!
从拳台上下来  奥基夫
Get out of the ring, O'Keefe.
我儿子迪奇才该在里面
My Dicky should be doing that.
迪奇不在  爱丽丝
Dicky ain't here, Alice.
米奇马上有场重要的比赛
Micky's got an important fight coming up
但他还没训练
and he's not training.
得了  别管他了
Forget about him. Never mind about him.
他没有尽到他应尽的责任
He's not doing what he's supposed to do with him.
就拿米奇来说...
Start saying to Micky...
这不是他的工作  好吗
He's not part of this, all right?
爱丽丝  他的训练方式不对
Alice, he's not being handled right.
我这么上镜可以吗
Did you get me coming in all right?
我要再来一遍吗
You want me to do it again?
从拳台上下来  奥基夫
Get out of the ring, O'Keefe.
-迪奇才是教练  -我是想帮忙  爱丽丝
- Dicky's the trainer. - I'm doing him favor, Alice.
你们来这边看看
I will show you over here
这是我收藏多年的剪贴簿
these scrapbooks I have been collecting for years.
米奇以前总黏着他哥哥
Micky used to follow his big brother everywhere.
他教给了你一切吧  亲爱的
Taught you everything, didn't he, honey?
1978年我们得到与苏格・雷・莱纳德对战的机会
In '78 we got the offer to fight Sugar Ray Leonard.
苏格・雷在马萨诸塞州
天哪  你们看过那片子吗
Oh, my God. Have you seen that video?
当然了  你们是HBO的人
Well, you're from HBO,
那就再看一次吧  片子呢
you've got to see it again! Come on. Where's the video at?
体育节目特别播报
今晚  我的儿子
Tonight my son is going to
将出乎所有人意料  击败苏格・雷・莱纳德
surprise everybody and beat Sugar Ray Leonard.
相信我  我知道
Believe me. I know it.
苏格・雷今晚也许会有些麻烦
Sugar Ray might have some trouble tonight.
这很有可能
That's a good possibility.
他今天的对手是位优秀的拳击手
He comes in here against a good boxer,
一个出拳凶猛的年轻人
a young man who can punch,
而这次在我看来
and I would like to say at this time
他们在身体上势均力敌
that physically they're just about equal.
莱纳德倒下了  这是不是致命一击呢
Leonard is down. Let's see if that's a knockout.
不可思议
This is unbelievable.
埃克伦德就这么轻易取胜了
Eklund just walked over there.
没人知道是怎么回事
Nobody seems to know what's happening.
迪奇成功了
Dicky did it.
Dicky did it!
你现在不是该在训练米奇吗
Aren't you supposed to be training Micky right now?
没有  9点钟再说
No, it ain't until 9:00.
迪奇  他妈的现在都11点45了
Dicky, it's fucking 11:45.
-11点三刻了  迪克  -啥
- 11:45, Dick. - What?
你他妈的把车停哪了  白痴
Where'd you fucking park the car, Boo Boo?
不是我停的  你停的
I didn't park it. You did.
你他妈摸摸口袋找找钥匙
Check your fucking pockets for the keys.
你拿着钥匙呢
You've got the keys, huh?
不是我停的  伙计
I didn't park it, man.
-没停在这  我不知道  -摸摸口袋
- Not here. I don't know... - Check your pockets, all right?
妈的  我跑着去  我他妈的得跑着去了
Oh, fuck it, I'll run. I need the fucking road work.
跑着去  你疯了吗
Road work? Are you crazy?
他很擅长跑步
He's a great runner.
-呱呱  -迪奇
- Quacker! - Hey, Dicky.
总比不来强
Better late than never.
看啊
Here, look.
警探大人在现场
Detectives on the scene...
得把这个带回去
Get to the bar with this...
-查清楚是怎么回事  -搞什么...
- Figure this one out, huh? - Why don't you...
等一下  我就有话直说了吧
Hold it. Hold it. Let me get this straight.
你们都是拳台外面
You guys are working in
米奇教练席上的吧
the same corner as Micky, together, right?
没错  他们都在我的教练席上
Yeah. Yeah, they're both in my corner.
-就是这样  -好吧  这肯定...
- This is what goes on. - Okay. It must be...
你难道不用工作吗
Don't you have a job to go to or something?
说真的  奥基夫有他的工作
Really, O'Keefe has a job that he should be at.
是啊  奥基夫警官在这儿加班
Yeah, Sergeant O'Keefe's working overtime here.
我们的对手是个老家伙
So we go at this old man:
犹太黑人  前任世界冠军
Jewish, black, former world champion.
我想我们做好了充分的准备
I think we've got all the bases covered.
我的弟弟  他连输了三场比赛
And my kid brother, he's lost three fights in a row.
他可不能这么一败涂地下去  心理上会有阴影
He can't get used to losing. It's a mental thing.
但我们会在麦比身上有所突破  是吧
But we're gonna break that with Mamby, right?
但愿如此  只要开始训练
Yeah, I hope. When we can train.
没错  训练  别浪费时间了  小米
When we train. Right. Don't be wasting time, Mick, you know?
-你还说浪费时间  -都他妈半天过去了
- Wasting time? - Half the fucking day's gone.
是吗  你也知道  我可是一直在等你
Yeah, half the day's gone. I've been waiting for you.
迅速  我们要击垮麦比  明白吗
Come on, move. We're going to outbox Mamby, huh?
猛击对方头部
Take it out on the head.
头部  身体  头部  连击
Head, body, head. That's your combo.
头部  身体  头部  身体
Head, body, head, body.
这是迪奇教他的
My Dicky taught him that.
苏格・雷也会去那
You know, Sugar Ray's going to be there
为ESPN做现场解说
calling the fight for ESPN.
我打败他后就再没见过他
I ain't seen him since I knocked him down,
大概有十四年了吧
like, fourteen years ago or something, right?
动点真格的吧
Let's get a real sparring going on here.
别给自己丢脸
Don't want to embarrass yourself.
你也不想在苏格・雷面前丢脸吧
Don't want to embarrass yourself in front of Sugar Ray, huh?
来吧  头部  身体  头部
Come on, head, body, head.
这拳威武  伙计
Your punch, man!
这才是你的水平  这就对了
That's your punch. Now that's your little punch.
你得使出全身的力道
Use your whole fucking body now.
乔治的手指肥得要死  拨电话都不行
George's fingers are so fucking big he can't even dial the phone!
做那手势也没用  乔治
That's not helping, George!
-等等  我有些晕了  -啥
- Wait, I'm confused. - What?
-我也有些晕  -我们都晕了
- I'm confused, too. - We're confused.
-乔治是谁的爹  -你晕了吗
- George is whose father? - You're confused?
老迪克・埃克伦德是迪奇  朵娜  盖尔和菲丽斯的爹
Dick Eklund Sr. is Dicky's, Donna's, Gail's and Phyllis' father.
-是迪克・埃克伦德  -对
- Is Dick Eklund. - Yeah.
而爱丽丝姓埃克伦德  辛蒂和凯茜也是
And even though Alice is an Eklund, so are Cindy and Cathy.
而乔治...
George is really...
-只有米奇  -不
- And Micky... - No.
我和米奇都姓沃德
Micky and I are Wards.
听着像是我和迪克・埃克伦德分开后
It's always sounded like Dick Eklund and I were separated, right?
乔治出现了  就是乔治
And then there was George. Just George.
-乔治是我男人  -乔治是咱爹
- George is my man. - George is our papa.
迪克之后又是乔治吗
After Dick, it was just George.
双关语 dick和george都用来形容巨大的老二
快点  过来
Come on. Come over here...
怎么不过去搭讪  她是个好女孩
Why don't you just go talk to her? She's a nice girl.
我跟她说过所有你的事
I told her all about you.
我不想约她  她肯定会拒绝
I don't want to ask her. She's going to say no.
能抗拒那美臀的诱惑吗
Can't beat that ass, can you?
快上  去吧  快去
Get at it. Go. Come on.
你准备就这么站着盯着我屁股看吗
Are you just going to stand there and stare at my ass?
你父亲也看  但他好歹和我讲话
Your father stares at my ass but he talks to me.
他觉得你是最棒的
He thinks you're the greatest.
他可没说你是新手
He didn't tell me you were new.
留着零钱吧  美人儿
Keep the change, doll.
他说你来找你的姐姐
He told me you came for you sister.
-这算小费吗  -没错  我给的小费
- This is a tip? - Yeah, that's my tip!
你知道这叮呤当啷的什么意思吗
You know what the bell says about this one?
下贱的小气鬼
Cheap bastard. Cheap fucker.
每天都来  还给我抠门的小费
Comes in every day, gives me shitty tips.
好吧  你也去死
Yeah, fuck you, too.
你是铺路的吧
You pave streets, right?
是的  我也是个拳击手
Yeah, I do. And I'm a fighter.
是吗  听说你是垫脚石
Oh, yeah. I heard you're a stepping stone.
我不是垫脚石
I'm no stepping stone.
他们利用你这种人
You're the guy they use
让其他拳击手踩着你往上爬
against the other fighters to move the other fighters up.
我之前是吃了几次败仗  但那不是我
I've had a few tough fights, but that's not who I am.
下场比赛我会使出真正的势力
The next fight's going to show who I am.
可不  他最后还是会输
Yeah, and he's going to lose that one, too.
威士忌苏打  夏琳  其中一杯我请你
Scotch and soda, Charlene. And one for yourself.
你那性感的屁股快给我动起来...
Now move that sugar ass...
放尊重些  不准冒犯她
Okay, be respectful. Don't disrespect her.
喂  别伤了你的手  你下周还要比赛
Hey, don't hurt your hand. You've got a fight next week.
再说你还得用那只手擦屁股呢
Besides, you wipe your ass with that one.
你赶紧给我滚
Don't wait up, or I'm going
不然让我逮着在车里揍死丫的  明白
to hit you in the car, sucker, all right?
这下他残了
He's gonna be so lame.
听懂了吗
All right? All right?
这样才对
That's right.
带上你的饮料  拿上饮料
Take your drink. He's taking his drink.
这家伙会成为冠军
This guy's going to be champion.
他很棒  是很出色的拳击手
He's a great guy. He's a great fighter.
好了  等等  谢谢你的饮料
Okay? Hold on. Thanks for the drink.
那些跟着他的摄像机是要给他拍电影
You know those cameras are making a movie about him?
要在HBO上播  他怎么击败了苏格・雷
He knocked out Sugar Ray Leonard on HBO.
所以他们一直扛着摄像机跟着他
That's why they're following him around with the cameras.
他们要拍部关于他回归的电影
They're making a movie about his comeback.
是啊  大家都在谈论这事
Yeah, everybody's talking about it.
那你是要和谁比赛
But who are you fighting?
-绍尔・麦比  -绍尔・麦比
- Saoul Mamby. - Saoul Mamby?
-什么人会起这种名字  -犹太黑人
- What kind of name is that? - Black and Jewish.
他们哪找的那么一个人
Where did they find a guy like that?
他可不是盖的  是前任世界冠军
He's no joke. Former world champion.
-前任世界冠军吗  -是啊
- Former champ? - Yeah.
-而我和他正好相配  -是吗
- I match up good with him, though. - Yeah?
-是的  -什么意思
- Yeah. - What does that mean?
我快熬出头了
Well, I got a light end, you know?
我打架很在行
I've got a reputation for brawling,
但我不和他打架
but I'm not going to brawl with him.
-我是和他打拳  -有区别吗
- I'm going to try to box him. - There's a difference?
当然  打架是要一决雌雄
Yeah, in brawling you slug it out.
你一拳我一拳
I hit you. You hit me.
而拳击则是一场博弈
Boxing is a chess game, you know?
得出招制胜
Got to pick my punches to take him down.
我的话就是头部  身体  头部  身体连击
I'm going head, body, head, body...
那是什么意思
What is head, body, head, body?
我先攻击他头部
Well, I hit him in the head,
他把手举起来防卫
then his hands got to go up to protect himself.
那身体就暴露了  我就打他身体
Opens up his body, then I hit him in the body,
接着他手缩回来  我又去打他头部
hand goes back down. I go back up to the head,
手又去护头  我就又打他的身体
hand goes back, and I hit him in the body.
不懂拳击的人
People who don't know fighting
觉得冲着头部去杀伤力最大
think you do a lot of damage hitting the head,
但其实你该重点攻击对方身体
but you actually do more hitting the body.
你觉得如何  我能约你出去吗
So what do you think? Can I take you out?
你结婚了吗
Are you married?
没有  我要是结婚了怎么还约你出去
No, would I ask you out if I was married?
你把我当成什么人
What kind of guy do you think I am?
这种事太常见了  相信我
Happens all the time, trust me.
我不是那种人
I'm not like that.
我没结婚  有一个女儿
I'm not married. I've got a daughter,
每隔一周见她一次
I see her every other weekend.
她叫凯茜  就这样
Her name is Kasie. But that's it.
拜托  和我约会吧
Come on, let me take you out.
什么时候
When?
周六晚上我就从亚特兰大回来了
Saturday night I'll be back in Atlantic City.
这是真号码吗
Is this the real number?
你打了就知道
You'll have to call it and see.
我会的
I will.
周六  一起吃晚饭和看电影
Saturday. Dinner and a movie.
你好吗
Hey. What's up?
米奇  还好吗
Micky, hey. How's it going?
我觉得萝莉现在不想见你
I don't think Laurie's expecting you right now.
他来这干什么  今天不是探视日  米奇
What's he doing here? This isn't your visitation day, Micky.
我只是想和凯茜打声招呼
I just want to say hi to Kasie.
今天不行  再见
It's not your day, goodbye.
是的  但我下周不在
Yeah, but I'm not around next week.
你连你探视的日子都不要了吗
Now you're ditching the days you do have?
不  我有比赛  我跟你说了
No, I have a fight. I told you that.
-吉米  -我不想被夹在中间
- Jimmy... - I can't get in the middle.
我和她说不通  所以我问你  吉米
I can't talk to her, okay? So I'm asking you, Jimmy.
我现在想和我女儿说话
I want to talk to my daughter now.
-和你爸聊聊  -该死的  吉米
- Talk to your father. - God damn it, Jimmy.
嗨  爸爸  你会打败绍尔・麦比
Hi, Daddy. - Daddy's gonna beat Saoul Mamby.
没错  我赢了之后呢
That's right. And I'm gonna tell you that after I win,
就能开始赚大钱
I'm gonna start making big money.
我就能搬去个大房子  我们说好的
And I'll move into a bigger apartment, like we talked about,
这样你就能多陪我几天
so you can live with me more days, okay?
好极了  更大的房子
Yeah, a bigger apartment!
-祝我好运吧  -你可别指望他  凯茜
- Wish me luck, all right? - Don't hold your breath, Kasie.
你怎么能这么误导自己女儿  米奇
It's cruel to mislead your child, Micky.
祝你好运  爸爸
Good luck, Daddy.
谢谢  凯茜  我爱你  亲爱的
Thanks, Kasie. I love you, honey.
回见  宝贝
Bye, baby.
-他人呢  -老天  真他妈耽误事
- Where is he? - Jesus Christ. Fucking holding us up.
担心个啥  有必要这么叹气嘛
Quit your worrying, for crying out loud.
烟喷了我一脸
All that shit in my face...
我知道这和我无关  我参加过很多次会面
I know it's none of my business. I go to a lot of meetings,
他们都说  随他去吧  让上帝做决定
and they have a saying: "Let go and let God."
你得随他去
You've got to let him go,
-小米  -他教会了我知道的一切
- Mick. - He's taught me everything I know.
只有他在场外才行  我一个人不行
He's been in my corner. I can't do it without him.
-你一个人已经做到了  -不  我不行
- You're already doing it without him. - No I'm not.
你当然可以
Yes you are.
听着  你知道他在哪
Look, you know where he is.
你干嘛不去接他
Why don't you just go get him?
你能去接他吗
Can you get him?
我他妈的可不去接他
I'm not fucking going to get him.
我们一伙人带着爱丽丝
Well are we all going to go over
坐着豪华汽车去接他吗  这样可不成
there in the limo with Alice? We can't do that.
迪奇
Dicky.
-你妈妈来了  -啥
- Your mother's outside. - What?
迪奇  你妈妈来了  她就在下面
Uh-oh, Dicky, your mother's outside. She's down there.
说我不在
I'm not here.
不要  迪奇  别这样
Don't, Dicky. Dicky! NO!
你他妈的搞什么
What the fuck are you doing?
你知道我们现在得赶去机场
You know we've got to go to the airport now.
我们要去赶飞机
We've got a flight to catch.
你也知道这场比赛对我很重要
You know how important this fight is to me.
-别跟妈说我在这  -可她知道
- Don't tell Mom I'm here, all right? - She knows.
-在房子后面等我  -你他妈到底...
- Pick me up back at the house, all right? - Are you fucking...
她现在就在房子前面
She's in the driveway right now.
好吧  快点  她就在前面
All right, but hurry up. She's in the fucking driveway.
我们要赶飞机
We've got a flight to catch.
你在你弟弟比赛前还这样
You do this on the day your brother's traveling?
-你们在搞什么  -只是小试牛刀
- What are you doing? - Just trying to see what I have.
你打他了吗
The fuck did you hit him for?
你为什么逼我打你
Why'd you make me do that to you?
-上帝  -天哪  迪奇
- Jesus! - Oh, my God, Dicky...
我正要走  妈
I was on my way, Mom.
-你们在干什么  -没事儿  妈
- What are you doing? - No, Mom. Mom...
我们还是快去机场吧
Why can't we just go to the fucking airport for once, please?
爱丽丝  你老公怎么办
Hey, Alice, what about your husband
他倒地不起了
who's laying on the fucking ground over here?
你不扶一下你老公吗
You want to help your husband?
你干什么呢
What are you doing,
跑过来像个该死的银背大猩猩
running in here like a silverback fucking gorilla?
-我们得抓住他  -是啊  你可抓住他了
- We had to get him, didn't we? - Oh, yeah, you got him, pal.
你看麦比
You see Mamby?
看到麦比的手臂是怎么抬的了吗
See how Mamby's arm comes up?
让他两侧留空
Leaves his side open,
然后就像弹球机一样打他
you just play him up like a pinball machine.
打得他尿血  你赢定了  小米  肯定能赢
He'll be pissing blood. No way you'll lose, Mick. No way.
-你好  卢  -好  迪奇
- Hey, Lou. - Dicky, boy.
听着  伙计
Hey listen, boy.
ESPN就不能提供好点的房间吗
ESPN can't get us better rooms than this?
现在我倒不为房间的事儿担心
I wouldn't worry about the rooms right now,
迪奇  你有更大的麻烦了
Dicky. You've got bigger headaches.
怎么了
Like what?
医生不允许麦比参赛
The doctor won't let Mamby fight.
为什么
Why not?
-他得了流感  -麦比得了流感吗
- He's got the flu. - Mamby got the flu?
是
Yeah.
迪奇  我们还是能参赛的
Dicky, we can still have a fight.
-对手是谁  -麦克・穆金
- With who? - Mike Mungin.
麦克・穆金是谁
Mike Mungin, who's that?
-来自费城  坐过牢  -出来有几个月了
- Guy from Philly. Been in prison. - He's been out a few months.
我所有人和地方都找过了
I've called everybody, checked everywhere.
只能找到他了
He's the only guy I could find.
前三场比赛很艰难  卢
My last three fights were rough, Lou.
我以为这场会轻松点
I mean this one's supposed to be easier.
我们训练时研究的是麦比
We've been fucking preparing for Mamby.
没错  但这家伙刚从班房里出来
Right, but this guy just came off the couch.
有好一阵子没打了
He's been sitting on his ass.
对米奇来说也许很轻松
Could be an easy win for Mick.
还记得乔伊・法雷吗  他曾把他打得很惨
Joey Farrell, remember him? He knocked his ass out.
而你曾把乔伊・法雷打得够呛
And you knocked down Joey Farrell...
没错  穆金刚从号子里出来
Exactly, and Mungin just got off the couch.
还没减肥  也许有些超重
Can't make weight. Might be a bit over, though.
超多少
How over?
-162  165的样子  -165磅
- 162, 165... - 165?
米奇减重了  他才146磅
Micky dropped weight. He's 146.
卢  我们为麦比备战的  明白吗
Lou, we prepared for Mamby, all right? We prepared for Mamby!
这家伙刚出来  而米奇状态正佳
This guy just got off the couch. Micky's in shape.
受过长跑等各种训练  而那家伙毛都没有
Road work, everything else. This other guy hasn't done dick.
别忘了  如果不参赛就没钱
Don't forget. You don't fight, nobody gets paid.
卢  请便
Lou, please...
好吧  乔伊・法雷都打败过他
All right. Um, Joey Farrell knocked him out...
肯定是场恶战  是吧
Going to be a hell of a fight, huh?
我不行  165磅太重了
I'm not doing this. 165 is big.
而你打败过乔伊・法雷
You knocked down Joey Farrell.
那又怎样  他可是中量级
So what? He's a middleweight.
可他刚从号子里出来
He just got off the couch.
他比我重20磅  迪奇
He's got twenty pounds on me, Dicky.
乔伊・法雷打败了他  而你打败过乔伊・法雷
Joey Farrell knocked him out. You knocked down Joey Farrell.
-话是这么说  -对  但你不能怕他
- You just said that. - Yeah but... You can't be scared.
-怕他吗  -是啊
- Scared? - Yeah.
那你怎么不跟他打去
Why don't you go fucking fight him?
我他妈的当然会  他不就是个胖子吗
I'll go fucking fight him. He's fat.
刚好重镇旗鼓  你就胜利回归了吧
Go snap out the teeth. It's your big comeback, right?
爱丽丝不正有此意吗
That's what Alice wants.
你打败过乔伊・法雷
You knocked down Joey Farrell.
好吧  我是打败过乔伊・法雷
All right, I knocked down Joey Farrell, okay?
但这家伙是中量级
But the guy is a middleweight.
我是次中量级
I'm a welterweight.
干脆让我跟重量级的去比好了
What, they don't have a fucking heavyweight to tow in there with me?
迪奇  告诉他  他能行  他绝对没问题
Tell him, Dicky. He can do it, right? He can do anything.
好的  爱丽丝  没问题
Yeah, Alice. No problem.
你现在从外面看吧
You watch from the outside now.
女士们先生们  有情"机枪手"麦克・穆金
Ladies and gentlemen, Mike "Machine Gun" Mungin!
沃德对决穆金  大西洋城  洲际赌场度假村
我靠
Holy shit!
看  那不是苏格・雷・莱纳德吗
Hey, look. There's Sugar Ray Leonard.
雷  苏格・雷  看这边
Hey, Ray. Sugar Ray. Over here.
迪奇  看他那块头
Dicky, come on. Look at the size of that guy.
-见鬼  -没错  真是见鬼
- Holy shit. - Yeah, holy shit.
他可不是次中量级
That guy's no welterweight.
米奇  要学会打无准备之战  现在正是时候
All right, Mick. Gonna have to learn to fuss you around. It's time now.
他根本不是刚从号子里出来
He did not just get off the fucking couch.
要真是这样  我也想去那号子蹲蹲看
If he did, I want to buy a couch like that.
我不管他是谁  我不在乎  看着我
I don't care who that guy is. I don't care. Look at me.
你是米奇・沃德
You're Micky Ward. You're Micky Ward.
第二回合
米奇・沃德的对手在比赛前一刻更换
Micky Ward fighting a last-minute replacement from Philadelphia,
来自费城的大块头
a much bigger man.
重拳猛击沃德
Punches smashing Ward.
沃德倒下了  沃德倒下了
Ward goes down! Ward goes down!
米奇  你到底怎么了  干掉他
Micky, what the fuck is wrong? Get rid of this dude!
穆金甚至不知道他今天要参赛
Mungin didn't even know he'd be fighting today...
加油  还击  小米
Come on, now, Mick!
沃德  值得尊敬的拳击手
Ward, a respected fighter.
希望这场实力悬殊之赛没伤到他的自尊
You hope this mismatch doesn't hurt his confidence.
-你是个失败者  -窝囊废
- You're a loser! - Loser!
你个失败者
You're a loser!
雷  喂  雷
Ray! Hey, Ray! Ray!
你好  迪奇
Hey, Dicky!
-最近怎么样  -还好
- How are you doing, man? - How are you?
165磅  ESPN耍了我们
165 pounds. ESPN screwed us.
-那家伙块头很大  -你知道我的意思吧
- The guy was huge. - You know what I'm saying?
我打败过雷
You know, I knocked Ray down.
虽然看起来不像  但我打败过雷
I look like shit, but I knocked Ray down.
请你们喝点什么吧  来杯冰的吧
Let me buy you guys a drink, all right? You want a cold one?
-不了  不了  -来一杯吧
- No, no, no... - A cold one!
我要走了  要赶飞机  下次吧
I've got to leave. I've got a plane to catch. Next time.
雷  HBO在拍摄关于我的片子
Hey, Ray. HBO is making a movie on me, you know?
他们能给你打电话吗
Can they call you?
我要参加场比赛
I'm going to get a fight.
看在老朋友的份上  希望你能来
I'd like you to be there, for old times' sake.
你可以给些评论
You can commentate or something.
影片是关于什么
What's the movie about?
重返赛场
My comeback, right?
-给我打电话  -我会的
- Call me. - I'll call you.
别装作不认识
Don't be a stranger.
他是我老朋友
He's my old pal.
-你要去医院吗  -怎么回事
- You going to the hospital? - What is that?
听着  米奇  你有过人的胆识
Look, Mick. Nobody's got heart like you.
你是个很有天赋的拳击手
You're a very talented fighter,
只是没打上合适的比赛
but you're not getting the right fights.
这会断送你的前程
It's killing your chances.
他跟麦克・托马说什么呢
What's he talking to Mike Toma about?
我怎么知道
I don't know what that is.
我会给你一次真正的机会
I want to give you a real shot.
希望你能来和我合作
I want you to come with me.
我出资让我的人训练你
I want to pay you to train with my guys.
-在哪儿  -拉斯维加斯
- Where? - Las Vegas.
趁还来得及做出正确的选择
Do it right and make one last run at this thing before it's too late.
那我哥哥怎么办
What about my brother?
恕我直言  他太会惹麻烦了
With all due respect, he's too much trouble.
你应该自己来拉斯维加斯
You owe it to yourself to come to Vegas.
米奇  想想看迪奇都对你做了什么
Come on, Mick. What has Dicky done for you?
他让你参加比赛
He gets you into fights.
还让你今晚被痛揍一顿
He lets you get beat like you did tonight.
你绝不该参加这种比赛
You know you never should have been in that fight.
你们差了18磅  好好想想吧
Eighteen pounds. Think of it that way.
是时候放弃了
You should have given it up.
滚下车去  说你呢
Get out of the car there. Come on, you!
-快坐下  -再给老妈来点威士忌
- Sit the hell down. - Just a little more scotch for Mom, okay?
就这样  很好
Here you go. Nice and easy.
别再过来了  老婆娘
Don't hurt yourself coming back, old broad.
上帝啊  那个苏格・雷
Oh, my God, that Sugar Ray...
长得还挺帅啊  是吧
He's a beautiful man, isn't he? Right?
真帅
A beautiful man.
你真该看看他看老妈的眼神
You should have seen the way he was looking at her.
-他人很好  -是个好人  我喜欢他
- He's a pretty man, huh? - He's a good guy. I like him. I know.
我在场边看见他了
I seen him ringside,
他看见我和米奇在一起特高兴
and he was so happy seeing me and Mick together.
那家伙很看重家庭
You know he's all about family, that guy.
和高兴看到家人团结在一起
Likes to see a family stick together.
小米  昨晚麦克・托马跟你说什么了
Mick, what'd Mike Toma want with you last night, huh?
他想让我去拉斯维加斯训练
He wants to train me in Vegas.
你不能信他  米奇  他不是家人  知道吗
You can't trust that guy, Micky. He ain't family, you know?
你不了解他
You don't know him.
他谈到我了吗  说我可以去吗
He say anything about me? He say I could come?
没提到你
He didn't mention you.
没你哥哥去拉斯维加斯干什么
What are you going to do in Vegas without your brother, huh?
那家伙只是利用你  当成厕纸一样
That guy just wants to use you, like a piece of toilet paper.
没有迪奇和家人  你去拉斯维加斯干什么
What are you going to do in Vegas without Dicky? Without your family?
我明白  我就这么跟他说
I know. That's what I told him.
你告诉他了  是吗
You told him that, right?
是  告诉他了  我说我要跟家人在一起
Yeah, I told him. I said I need to be with my family.
这就对了  话说得没错
That's right. Nothing wrong with that.
苏格・雷说给他打电话  我们给他打吧  宝贝
Sugar Ray said call him. We're going to call him, baby.
你们想试试吗
You guys can spar a little, right?
我的宝贝  爸爸回来了
There's my champ. Daddy's home. Daddy's home!
爱你
I love you...
脸还疼吗  宝贝
Your face hurting you, sweetheart?
我心疼死了
Because it's killing me.
-没事  -米奇叔叔赢了吗
- Come on... - Uncle Micky win the fight?
没有  米奇叔叔没赢  这次没赢
No, Uncle Micky didn't win this time. Not this time.
小米  保重  明天给你打电话
Hey, Mick. Take care. I'll call you tomorrow.
振作点  我们还有别的比赛呢
Cheer up. We'll get you another fight.
我不知道  妈  我不想再打下去了
I don't know, Mom. I don't think I want to do this no more.
那你想干什么
What don't you want to do no more?
我只是不想再打了
I just don't want to do it anymore.
-你说什么呢  -小米
- What are you talking... - Hey, Mick.
ESPN耍了我们  他们欠我们
ESPN screwed us. They owe us.
我们还能有别的比赛  等你好点了
We'll get another fight. You heal up.
-没事的  -听你哥哥的没错
- It'll be okay. - Yeah, listen to your brother.
他们欠我们太多了  宝贝
They owe us big-time, sweetheart.
也许他们会准备个迪奇的回归之战
Hey, maybe they'll even do Dicky's comeback fight.
你觉得呢
What do you think, huh?
没事的  振作点  到家后好好洗洗
Oh, come on. Cheer up. You take a little soap when you get home.
这一两天想想
Have a day or two to think about it.
我会给你找到一场好赛事  宝贝
I'll find you a better fight, sweetheart.
更好的  我会跟他们谈
Much better fight. I'm going to talk to them.
-看在上帝的份上  爱丽丝  -干嘛
- For Christ's sake, Alice. - What?
他刚打输比赛  别烦他了
He's been through the ringer. Leave him alone.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
-让他单独待会  -你脑子有毛病吗
- Leave him some time to himself. - What is your fucking problem?
米奇呢  他不进来吗
Where's Micky? Is Micky not going to come in?
他不进去了  他要回家休息
No, he's not coming in. He needs to get back and get some rest.
来吧  咱们先进去吧
Come on. Let's go inside.
他需要休息  他心情很不好
He's going to go rest. He's all grumpy.
他累了  打输了  感觉有些丢脸
He's tired. He's beat up. He's a little embarrassed, I think.
谁
Who is it?
我看到你的影子了
I saw the shade move.
米奇  影子还在动  我看到你来窗前了
Micky, the shade is still moving. I saw you come to the window.
我知道你就在那
I know you're in there.
你好歹开个门
The least you can do is open up this door
亲口告诉我昨天为什么没给我打电话
and tell me to my face why you didn't call me yesterday.
昨晚为什么放我鸽子
Why did you stand me up last night?
我想打来着  就要打了  但是没打
I started to call. I was going to call. I just couldn't.
因为你输掉了比赛吗
Because you lost the fight?
也许是吧  因为我输了
Maybe, yeah. Because I lost the fight.
你怎么知道我住这
How do you know my house anyway?
我问了我哥哥
I asked my brother.
你流血了  那边也流了
Your thing's coming off. And your other thing.
还有药布吗
You got any tape?
这是那个黑犹太人打的吗
Did the black Jewish guy do this to you?
我没跟他打
I didn't get to fight the black Jewish guy.
没用那招头部身体连击法吗
You didn't get to go head, body, head?
绍尔・麦比得了流感
Saoul Mamby got the flu.
有个比我重20磅的家伙取代了他
Guy that took his place had twenty pounds on me.
我不可能打败他
I never should have fought him.
那你为什么参赛
Why did you?
不参赛就没钱
Nobody would have got paid.
他们都说我能打败他
Everybody said I could beat him.
他们是谁
Who's everybody?
我妈和我哥
My mother and my brother.
你还带我去吃晚餐看电影吗
So are you going to take me to dinner and a movie, or what?
-你真美  -谢谢
- You look great. - Thank you.
房子也很漂亮
You've got a nice house, too.
这是幢公寓楼
It's an apartment building.
有五间公寓
There's five of them in there.
我和一个室友一起住
One of my old roommates lives with me.
室友  你参过军吗
Roommate? What, were you in the army?
-上过大学  -大学
- College. - College? Wow.
是啊  真是大有帮助  现在却成了个酒吧女
Yeah, a lot of good it did me. I work in a bar.
看着你很喜欢  你在那边很受欢迎
You seem to enjoy it. Very popular down there.
是啊  受欢迎  我得离开那地方
Ugh, yeah. Popular. I've got to get out of there.
如果我上班时不喝酒  就完蛋了
If I don't drink while I'm working I'll fucking kill myself.
-哪所大学  -罗德岛大学  全船奖
- What college? - URI. Full boat.
-全船奖是奖学金的一种吗  -是
- A full boat's a scholarship, right? - Yeah.
你什么运动突出
For what?
-我曾是个跳高运动员  -跳高运动员
- I was a high-jumper. - High-jumper?
开玩笑呢吧
You've got to be kidding me.
去你的  我那时很厉害
Fuck you. I was good.
新英格兰冠军  五英尺八英寸
I was New England champ. I cleared 5'8".
但没毕业  整天参加派对
Never graduated. I partied too hard.
你吗
You?
为什么到莱克星顿来腐败
What are we doing in richie-rich Lexington?
你常来这家电影院吗
You come to this theater a lot?
是啊  这家电影院不错  经常有好片子
Yeah, it's a good theater. They've got good movies here.
-是吗  比如呢  -食欲线索
- Yeah? Like what? - Belly Epi-cue.
我觉得应该是铃声年代
I think it's Bell Epic.
是年代  铃声年代
It's epic. Bell Epic.
美好年代  纽约时报上这么写
Belle Epoque. The New York Times don't lie.
我怎么没听说过
Well I never heard of it.
你是在哪儿听说的  纽约时报吗
Where'd you hear about it? The New York Times?
不是  一个同事说的
No, a guy from work.
这部片子的摄影艺术应该很棒
And the cinematography is supposed to be gorgeous.
那很好
Oh. Cool.
你喜欢这部电影吗
That's the movie you wanted to see?
里面甚至都没什么激情镜头
There wasn't even any good sex in it.
整场还得看字幕  烦人的字幕
Had to read the whole fucking movie. Fucking subtitled.
修路队的人向你推荐的吗
Some guy from a road crew recommended it to you?
带字幕的电影
A fucking subtitled movie?
怎么了
What's going on, huh?
到底怎么了  你有女朋友了吗
What's going on? You got a girlfriend or something?
瞒着她跟我交往吗
You hiding me from her?
我没有女朋友  好吗
I don't have a girlfriend, all right?
我喜欢你
I like you.
我来这是因为我不想让洛厄尔的人看到我
I came here because I don't want to show my face in Lowell.
我跟所有人说我会赢那场比赛
I told everybody I was going to win that fight
回来后会走入正轨
and get back on track.
我告诉我女儿
I told my daughter I was going
我要买幢大房子  那样她就可以住进来了
to get a bigger apartment so she could move in.
你以为我不想给你打电话吗
You don't think I wanted to call you?
我没脸见你
I was embarrassed.
我讨厌做个失败者
I'm sick of being a fucking disappointment.
你真以为你的家人关心你吗
You really think your family is looking out for you?
别那样说  我不喜欢
Don't say that. I don't like that.
你告诉我经过后我还能怎么说
What else I can say after what you told me?
瞧瞧你的脸
Look at your face.
看你这样子
Look at you.
去你的  卢
Bullshit, Lou.
我会一直给你打电话
I'm not going to stop calling until
你得给我们安排场比赛做弥补
you make this right and get us a fight that's fair.
我儿子上次差点被打死
My boy could have got killed last time.
什么样的
Yeah, like what?
别告诉我他刚从号子里出来就行
Just don't tell me he just got off the fucking couch.
走出失败的阴影吗
Coming off a loss?
听起来不错  回头找你
That sounds very interesting. I'll get back to you.
这有个大好机会
Got a great opportunity here.
我们得把米奇找来
We've got to go find Micky.
我们大概三星期没见过他了
Nobody's seen him for, like, three weeks.
老天
Jesus...
以前都是迪奇没人影  现在他俩都这样了吗
Used to be Dicky we couldn't find. Now it's both of them?
妈  我想他跟那个酒吧女在一起
Mom, I think he's with that girl from the bar.
-什么女孩  -就那个叫夏琳的妞
- What girl? - It's that fucking girl, Charlene.
在酒吧工作  他俩在一起
That's who he's with. That girl from the bar.
乔治一直想撮合他们一起
George was all fucking eager for them to get together.
-我听说她经常玩3P  -和其他女孩一起
- I heard she's into three-ways. - Yeah, with other girls.
对  就像那些MV女郎
Yeah, like one of those MTV girls.
MV女郎  你们说什么呢
MTV girls? What are you talking about?
淫荡得很
Wild.
装腔作势的  就因为她上过大学
She acts all fucking superior because she went to college.
你们几个快去找米奇
You girls just go find your brother Micky.
告诉他我有重要事跟他商量
Tell him I've got important business to discuss.
我去找迪奇
I've got to go find Dicky.
迪奇
Dicky!
妈  不是这样的  只是
Hey, Mom. It's not... It's just...
这是朋友的房子
It's just a friend's house.
拜托  别生气了
Come on, whatever.
我开了个玩笑
I started a joke,
全世界却为之哭泣
which started the whole world crying.
假如我知道
Oh, if only I'd seen
那只是在取笑自己
that the joke was on me.
我会哭泣
I started to cry,
全世界却为之而笑
which started the whole world laughing.
假如我知道
Oh, if only I'd seen
那只是在取笑自己
that the joke was on me.
我会仰望天际
I looked at the skies,
在眼前挥舞双手
running my hands over my eyes,
接着我跌下床
and I fell out of bed,
撞破头...
hurting my head...
你是"海狸"  你是"红熊"
So you're Beaver, and you're Red Bear.
"红胡子"
Red beard.
她是"红狗"  那是"海狸"
She's Red Dog, and that's Beaver.
你是"红狗"  你是"海狸"
You're Red Dog. You're Beaver.
别叫那些名字  家里人才能叫
Yeah, don't use those names. It's just for family.
客气点
Be nice.
不要叫昵称
Don't use the nicknames.
那我他妈的该叫她们什么
What the fuck will I call them then?
说到家人...
Speaking of family...
你好
Hello.
-爱丽丝  这位是夏琳  -你好
- Alice, this is Charlene. - Hi.
我听过你很多事
I've heard a lot about you.
是吗  我也听过你很多事
Really? I've heard a lot about you, too.
-你什么意思  -和你一样的意思
- What's that supposed to mean? - Same thing you meant.
我们能坐下好好谈正事吗
Can we just sit down and talk about business?
小米  我又帮你组织了场拳赛
I got you another fight, Mick.
正如我承诺过那样
Just like I said I would.
卢和ESPN给我们的补偿
Lou Gold and ESPN made it right.
正如我所说
Just like I told you.
对手是乔・梅伦克  六周后在快活赌场
Joe Melenk. Six weeks. Foxwoods.
他是个...  十二分把握  他什么都不是
He's a... Ten in eight. He's none.
报酬是两万美元
And they're going to pay us twenty grand.
准确地说是17500美元
$17,500, technically.
好吧  17500美元也很可观了  小米
All right, $17,500, which is still good money, Mick.
是啊
Yeah.
那是很好  迪克
That's good, Dick.
我只想弄清楚怎样最合适我
I'm just trying to figure out what's best for me.
比方说呢
Like what, huh?
什么最合适你  亲爱的
What's best for you, sweetheart?
得了吧  小米  我想你会很激动
Come on, Mick. I thought you'd be more excited.
你怎么不激动呢
Why aren't you more excited?
这场比赛有把握  报酬也不错
It's a good fight, good money.
我和卢・金谈好了
I got something with Lou Gold.
他了解我们
He knows us.
我知道  妈妈
I know, Mom.
我只是不想再这样下去
I just don't want things going the way they've been going.
小米  上场比赛不公平  那不公平
Mick, that last fight was unfair. That was unfair.
我们不会再重蹈覆辙
And we ain't going to repeat that,
-对吗  -绝对不行
- right? - Oh, not on your life.
老弟  你只要上了拳台就行
You know, buddy, it's just you in the ring.
是的  我知道是我上拳台
Yeah, I know it's just me in the ring.
但我不喜欢这里处理事情的方式
But I don't like the way things have been going here.
-哪里  -哪里
- Where? - Where?
这里  这些  我们  洛厄尔的一切
Here, this, us, Lowell, the whole routine.
-乔治  你别管  -都是你们在说
- George, stay out of it! - You're doing all the talking.
-听他说  -我是在问他
- Let him talk. Listen. - I'm asking him.
-你是在命令他  你听他说  -你别管
- You're telling him. Listen. - Stay out of it.
别这么和我说话
Hey, don't tell me to stay out of it.
小米  到底是什么问题
Mick, what's the problem?
-很多问题  -那都是些什么问题
- Problems. - What problems?
-问题是...  -比如说呢
- Problems... - Like what?
比如说  训练时你没准时到
Like maybe you not showing up on time to train.
比方说  快上飞机的时候
Like maybe him having to come find you in a crack house
他还不得不去毒品屋找你
when you're supposed to be at the airport.
不好意思  我不认识你  说什么呢
I'm sorry. I don't know who you are. Why are you talking?
我是夏琳  我们才认识
I'm Charlene. We just met.
我们在一起  是不是要再来一遍  你好  我是夏琳
We're together. Do we need to do this again? Hi, I'm Charlene.
-你好  夏琳  -你好
- Hi, Charlene. - Hi.
-你好  我是夏琳  -你好  夏琳
- Hi, I'm Charlene. - Hi, Charlene.
我们在一起了
Hey, we're together.
你想什么呢  小米
What are you going to do, Mick?
听个在酒吧干活的"MV女郎"瞎掰吗
Listen to some MTV girl who works in a bar?
她懂个屁拳击
What does she know about boxing?
我只知道  他们在维加斯
I know they're going to Vegas
能领到薪水还能接受全年训练
and getting paid to train year-round.
这听起来可比
Sounds a hell of a lot better than
你们的计划好多了
what you've got him doing here.
你就这样让她和你妈说话吗
You going to let her talk like that to your mother?
得了吧  米奇
Come on, Micky.
我告诉过你  我们在一起
I told you, we're together.
这是我女友  我想让她待这里
This is my girlfriend. I want her here.
我所做的一切都是为了你  米奇
I have done everything. Everything I could for you, Micky.
结果这个MV女郎一来...
This MTV girl comes along...
别再叫我"MV女郎"了  不管他妈的是什么意思
Stop calling me an MTV girl, whatever the fuck that means.
-烂货  -荡妇
- Skank. - Wild.
我干这行超过十五年了
I've been doing this over fifteen years.
她来了  对我不敬...
She comes in, disrespects me...
她没想要对你不敬  好吗
She don't mean no disrespect, okay?
我有机会赚钱接受全年训练
I had a chance to get paid to train year-round.
全年的  明白吗  这就是她的意思
Year-round, okay? That's all she's talking about.
我希望能得到你们的支持
I would hope that you guys could appreciate that.
我认同你的想法  好吧
I know what you're talking about, all right?
我能搞定
I could have had that.
如果你愿意  我会想办法搞定
You know, I had opportunities like maybe you're going to have.
你想要钱去全年训练  对吗
Now, you want money so you can train year-round? Yeah?
我会帮你搞到钱  你就可以去全年训练
I'll get you money so you can train year-round.
-你行吗  -我会去办
- You? - Yeah, I'll do it.
-相信我  -怎么弄
- Trust me. - How?
相信我  好吗
Hey, trust me, all right?
说定了
Done.
行吗  夏琳  你觉得呢  大家呢
All right? Charlene? Yeah? Everyone?
你投入200美元
So you put in $200...
再找十个人每人投入200美元
Then you get ten other people to put in $200...
这样你就能得到2000美元
And you've got your $2000.
每个人给你200美元吗
Everybody give you $200?
不是每个人  只是你们中的十个
No, not everybody. Just ten of you.
十个幸运者
Ten lucky ones.
-你要骗我们  -不  不是的
- You'll rip us off. - No, no.
-就是给你个机会  -那你给我200美元
- Give you an opportunity. - You give me $200!
不  你把这个机会给其他十个人
No, you get that from ten other people
你从他们手里赚这笔钱
who you offer the opportunity to.
对吗  你懂不懂
Right? You understand? No?
他觉得你把柬埔寨人都当傻瓜
He thinks you think Cambodian people are stupid.
我爱柬埔寨人
I love Cambodian people!
看看凯伦
I mean, look. Look at Karen.
她是我女朋友  她很美  我爱她
She's my girlfriend. She's beautiful. I love her.
还有布莱恩  我们是同事
And Brian. We work on a road crew together.
最近不咋见了
Not so much lately.
布莱恩  我们是同事
Brian, we work on a road crew together.
我的意思是很久没见你了
You haven't been showing up, that's what I'm saying.
这和柬埔寨人没关系
This isn't any kind of Cambodian thing.
白人之间也常这么干
White people do this to other white people.
这世界就是这样
It's what makes the world go around.
我觉得那没什么用
I don't think that's helping.
这可是千载难逢的机会...
This is a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity...
我是说他们不懂
I mean, they didn't understand.
他们一直看我的比赛...
They're practically on my game...
通常都会听我的
Usually they listen to what I say,
但他们不懂得抓住机会
but they just didn't understand the opportunity.
我是说那机会难得
I mean, it was awesome.
我们聊到哪了
What were we talking about?
-就在你和苏格・雷比赛前  -对  对  对
- Before you fought Sugar Ray. - Right, right, right.
苏格・雷的故事太多  发生得太快
Sugar Ray was too much, too soon.
我得慢慢回忆
I needed to build up slow.
这电影是什么主题来着
What's this movie about again?
我说过  是关于毒瘾
I told you, it's about crack addiction.
让孩子们真实感受到吸毒者的生活
Showing what it really is so kids can see it for real.
操  我们得帮小米赚到那笔钱
Fuck. We've got to get Mick's money.
棒极了
Yeah! That was awesome!
-下车  -操
- Get out of the car! - Oh, shit!
将双手放在车顶
Put your hands on the roof!
将双手放在车顶  就这样
Put your hands on the roof, that's it!
-掏空你的口袋  -你是警察吗
- Empty your pockets. - Are you a cop?
他妈的滚到人行道上
Get on the fucking sidewalk,
走  他妈的走啊  不要回头
move! Fucking move! Don't turn around!
不要回头  我们要开走你的车
Don't turn around! We'll have to take your vehicle.
-那我怎么回家  -那是你的问题
- How am I going to get home? - That's your problem.
我们赚到多少  数一数
How much we got here? Count it.
他妈的搞毛
What the fuck?
就是那家伙
That's the guy!
他这样诈过我  他又干上了
He did it to me and he's doing it again!
马上趴在地上
Get on the ground right now!
沃伯赛事中心  3月7日星期六  下午7点半  劲爆开战
开门  他妈的让我进去
Open the door! I've got to get off the fucking street!
他妈的快让我进去
I'm trying to get off the fucking street!
是迪奇  操蛋的条子在打他
It's Dicky. The cops are fucking punching him.
他们在揍他  他需要帮忙
They're beating him. He needs help.
坐着别动  别起来
Stay here. Don't get up. Stay here.
听他的  别去
Listen to him. Stay right here.
他妈的你开玩笑吗
Are you fucking kidding me?
他妈的这是搞什么
Hey what the fuck? Come on.
把他关车里就行了  你们用不着那样
Just put him in the car. You don't need to do that.
你也想搅进来吗  现在你也有份了
Want to get involved? Now you're involved.
放开我弟弟  不然我杀了你
Get out of my brother, or I will kill you.
他是拳击手  他妈的打烂他的手
He's a fighter. Break his fucking hands
我什么也没干
I do nothing.I do nothing.
米奇  你的手...你的手...
Micky your hand... Your hand...
分开押送  分开关押
Separate cars, separate cells.
我可不想让他们串通正当防卫口供
I don't want them making up some bullshit defense story.
来吧  兄弟们  该回家了  走吧
Come on, folks, time to go home. Let's go.
-迪奇  -搞什么
- Hey, Dicky! - What the fuck, man?
-迪奇  -上帝啊
- Dicky! - Jesus Christ.
他的手...
His hands...
又见面了  迪奇  进来过27次了啊
Welcome back, Dicky. That's 27 arrests.
沃德: 被控一项扰乱治安
Ward: One count of disturbing the peace,
缴纳保证金后予以保释
released on your own recognizance.
埃克伦德: 被控三项袭击挑衅警官
Eklund: Three counts of assault and battery on a police officer,
两项拒捕
two counts of resisting arrest,
两项盗窃
two counts of larceny from a person,
两项冒充警官
two counts of impersonating a police officer.
保释金为25000美元
Bail set at $25,000.
案件自今日起两周后继续审理
Case continued two weeks from today.
我想了解一下357号文件
I'm wondering about the File 357.
此外请给我卷宗复印件
I need a copy of the discovery report, as well.
-小米  你会说是自卫吧  -什么
- Mick, you're going to say it was self-defense, right? - What?
你说是自卫  好吗
You're going to say it was self-defense, right?
你走出来  你看到他们在打我
You came outside, you seen them beating on me.
我什么也没干
I didn't do nothing.
我只是待在外面和其他人一样
I was just waiting outside like anybody else.
小米  我是为了你
Mick, I was doing it for you.
-为了我吗  -是啊
- You did it for me? - Yes.
把我害成这样吗  帮我个忙
This? Do me a favor.
他妈的以后别为我做任何事了  好吗
Don't do fucking nothing for me no more, okay?
我可不会为你撒谎
I'm fucking dont lying for you.
没有我你要怎么办
What are you going to do without me, huh?
这事情不该是这样
Huh? This ain't how it was going to go down.
他们应该把我直接塞到车里
They should have just put me in the car, huh?
小米  别这样  小米
Mick, come on! Mick!
迪奇  近来如何
Dicky, hey! What's up, Dicky?
不就是他嘛
Hey, that's the man!
你可打败了苏格・雷呢
Hey, you knocked out Sugar Ray!
迪奇  迪奇  迪奇
Dicky! Dicky! Dicky!
谁
Who is it?
我不想见你  米奇
I don't want to see you, Micky.
夏琳
Charlene...
我做不到
I can't take it.
我不想被你或你家人拖累
I'm not going to let you or your family drag me down.
我不干了  夏琳  好吗
I'm quitting, Charlene, okay?
我不打拳击了  我也不要再比赛了
I don't fighting. I don't need it anymore.
-这他妈的太蠢了  -什么  为什么
- That's fucking stupid. - What? Why?
因为这太悲哀了
Because it's sad that
你就这么被他们那愚蠢的一套随意糊弄
you let them take it away from you with their stupid bullshit.
我还能做什么  夏琳
What else I can do, Charlene?
你还有很多事可做  米奇
There's a lot you can do, Micky.
你父亲希望和那人合作
There's this guy that your dad wants you to meet,
而你觉得你没了迪奇就不行
you just don't think you can do it without Dicky.
夏琳
Charlene...
-别再找我  -别这样
- Don't call. - Come on.
别找我了  好吗
Don't call me, okay?
迪奇  你很痛苦吧
Hey, Dicky, you hurt bad?
可怜的混球
Poor fucker.
米奇  把另一个桶拿过来
Hey, Micky, bring another bucket, huh?
很好
Good.
本周五  HBO原创纪录片为你介绍
And this Friday, an HBO original documentary.
马萨诸塞州  洛厄尔的迪克・埃克伦德
Right here in Lowell, Mass., the story of Dick Eklund,
昔日的拳坛新星  今日的阶下囚
the once promising boxer who turned criminal.
看谁来了
Oh, look who it is.
那是...迪奇的弟弟
That's... That's Dicky's brother.
-你好  米奇  -老样子
- Hey, Micky. - Regular.
-还好吗  伙计  -看谁来了
- Hey, what's up, man? - Look who's here.
-见到你很高兴  兄弟  -你好
- Good to see you, bro. - How are you doing?
感觉如何  你的手还好吗
How you feeling? How's the hand?
-差不多好了  -看起来好多了
- Uh, it's getting there. - Looks better.
你怎么不来体育馆了
Why don't you come down to the gym?
如果你愿意  我帮你训练
We'll work out, if you want.
你他妈的还真胖  快成猪了
You fat fuck, you're getting big.
是啊  我知道  只是...
Yeah, I know. It's just...
帮我父亲修修屋顶  多点时间陪陪凯茜
Roofing for my father and spending more time with Kasie.
顺便  那电影在HBO播了  伙计
By the way, this movie on HBO, man.
你们这帮家伙看什么看
What are you boys looking at?
那电影拍的是他那疯子哥哥  又不是他
The movie's not about him. It's about his crazy brother.
我得走了
I should go.
-小米  回体育馆来吧  -再见  小米
- Come back to the gym, Mick. - Bye, Mick.
别看那傻逼电影  别看
Don't go watch that crazy shit on TV. Don't.
进军好莱坞喽...
Going to Hollywood...
好戏开场
Let's get this started!
洛厄尔曾是美国
Lowell was the birthplace
工业革命的发源地
of the Industrial Revolution in America.
-那是...  -人们前来寻找...
- Oh, that's... - These people came to find...
美国瘾君子
我以前住那里
I used to live over there.
在这镇上有段美好的回忆
This town's got good memories, right?
-看看  -可不是
- Check it out. - Fuck yeah.
这边这所房子  那白房子...
This house right up this way, the white house...
-看到了  -我第一次吸毒就在这
- Oh, yeah! - First time I got my crack over here.
你知道他们在"白宫"里也吸毒吗
Did you ever know they smoke crack at the white house?
我第一次干吸毒这档子事
The first time I did crack or whatever,
大概是在二十三岁
I was about twenty-three.
我一哥们给了我一点尝了下
A friend of mine gave me a gram or whatever.
我真他妈希望这没发生过
Fuck I wish that never happened.
在那之前  我本想去参加银手套联赛之类
Before that, I'd be doing the silver mittens and stuff.
只有我是孩子  当时才12岁  醉得一塌糊涂
I was the only kid. I'd be twelve. I'm shit-faced.
我来告诉你吸毒是什么感觉
I'll tell you how crack was.
它会进入你的肺  等它进去后
It enters your lungs. When it enters your lungs,
-我想看爸爸  -上帝啊
- I want to watch Daddy. - Oh, my God.
不行的  亲爱的  回楼上去
No, sweetie. You go back upstairs.
但我想看电视上的爸爸
But I want to watch Daddy on TV.
不行  现在你不能看你爸爸  好吗
No, you can't. You can't watch Daddy now, all right?
你回楼上睡觉  好吗
You go back upstairs and go to bed, okay?
这是我兄弟  来看看
Okay, this is my boy, here. Check it out.
今天我能卖你什么  一条蟒蛇吗
What... What can I sell you today? A python?
好啊  拿来看看  老兄
Yeah, check it out, man.
他们会替我买单
They're going to buy me some.
有一阵子了  现在来什么我都能行
It's been a while. I'll take anything right now.
从未想过我会去亲条蛇
Never thought I'd kiss a fucking snake.
我倒是经常梦到  但...
I always dreamed about it, but...
你嗑药嗑嗨了啥破事都干过  是吧
You do a lot of shit when you're high, right?
见鬼  是的  让洛厄尔举世瞩目了
Heck, yeah. Put it all on the map.
你击倒了苏格・雷  你不是说过吗
You knocked Sugar Ray Leonard down, didn't you say?
是的  他击倒了他
Yeah, he knocked him down,
但我觉得那不算击倒
but I don't think it was a knockout.
我觉得他是滑倒的
I think he slipped.
他击倒了他
He knocked him down.
-他不是滑倒  -他就是滑倒的
- He didn't slip. - He slipped.
-杰克...  -得了吧
- Oh, Jack... - Come on.
他妈的骗人
That's a fucking lie!
他们说他惹上了毒瘾...
They say he's in trouble with drugs...
你们在干嘛
What are you doing?
你是不是在诋毁我们家人
Are you talking shit about the family?
没  根本没有
No, not at all.
我听到你们在说
Yeah. I heard you say.
我们不喜欢这样
We're not like that.
洛厄尔根本不是那么回事
This is not what Lowell is all about.
我原以为他会浪子回头
I thought he could make a comeback
成为我们的骄傲  但他没有
and make us proud, but he didn't.
我不知道迪奇怎么想
I don't know what Dicky was thinking.
让人觉得又讨厌又失望
Very disappointing. Very disgusting.
你让洛厄尔城倒退三十年
You brought the city of Lowell back thirty years.
我们很不满意
We're not happy.
-你好  -吉米
- Hello? - Jimmy.
你能不能帮我个忙
Hey, will you do me a favor?
别让凯茜看HBO的电影
Make sure Kasie's not watching HBO?
其实我们现在正看着  小米
Actually, we were watching it right now, Mick,
但不用担心  我会处理...
but don't worry about it. I got it...
我就想让她看看
I want her to see it.
让她看看她叔叔是什么人
Let her see who her uncle is.
-什么  -你又是什么人
- What? - Who you are.
我是什么人  你说什么呢
Who I am? What are you talking about?
得让孩子了解真相  小米
Kids need to know the truth, Mick.
萝莉  求你了  快关掉
Laurie, turn it off, please.
她没必要看这些
She does not need to see this.
她没必要看到  她只是个孩子
She doesn't need to see it. She's a kid.
你要是嗑了药
If you're on crack,
就会感到飘飘欲仙
you feel so much lighter.
感到青春焕发
You know, you feel young.
所有的东西都那么好笑
And everything is so funny.
所有的东西都...
Everything is just...
接着所有的东西都不好笑了
Everything is... It wasn't funny.
接着就没感觉了
And then it fades,
你会想再爽一下
then you've got to get high again.
你那部分电影该结束了
Your part of the movie's going to end
之后你就去坐牢了
with you going to jail.
我们了解迪奇  我们会照顾他的吧
We know Dicky. We're going to take care of him, huh?
你们不能告诉他
You guys can't talk to him.
关掉那该死的东西  快关掉
Turn that shit off. Turn this off, all right?
关掉它  你关不关
Turn it off. Will you turn this off?
你不关  那他妈的我来关
You don't turn this off. I'm turning it fucking off.
那是我的生活  他妈的那可是我的生活
Hey, that's my life. That's my fucking life up there.
-我就想看  我无所谓  -去你妈的鬼
- I want to watch this. I don't care. - I will fuck you up.
你他妈的欠揍吗  劝你别惹我
You fucking want some? Don't fucking try me.
我他妈的可还是狠角色  你是想挨揍吗
I still fucking won it, okay? You fucking want some?
那是我儿子  你敢嘲笑他吗
That's my son there. You're laughing at him?
那是我儿子  他在哭
That's my son, he's crying,
他需要我  而我他妈的还被困在这
he needs me, and I'm fucking stuck in here?
米奇  你在看吗
Micky, are you watching this?
他们对我们都干了些什么
What are they doing to us?
我不知道怎么和你说
I don't know what to tell you.
这些年来你都假装视而不见
You're pretending like you don't know what's going on.
他这样都好几年了
He's been doing this for years.
我知道这很可怕  但是妈...
Yeah, I know it's horrible, Mom. But...
你又怎么看
What do you think?
你觉得是他们陷害他的吗
You think they set him up?
妈  你觉得他都在干嘛
Mom, what do you think he was doing?
是他们给他钱
You know, they gave him money,
给他毒品在电影里抽  是吧
gave him drugs for the movie, right?
米奇
Micky?
-换了新沙袋吗  -对
- You got a new bag, huh? - Yup.
-还有新的支架  -对
- New bracket, too? - Yup.
-这沙包怎么回事  -不知道
- What happened to the peanut? - Don't know.
像个沙滩球
Like a beach ball.
不错
Good job.
-小米  这是萨尔・拉纳诺  -小米  最近好吗
- Mick, Sal Lanano. - Hey, Mick. How you doing?
你是个出租车公司的老板吧
You own the cab company. Good businessman, right?
他做生意很有一套
He's very organized.
-手怎样了  -还行  挺好
- How's the hand? - It's good, you know?
好多了  能用上力了
It's getting better. Stronger.
我之前打了几通电话
You know, I made a few calls already.
我和布迪・泰格谈过了
I just talked to Buddy Tags.
他说能给安排几场地区赛
He said he can set up something local.
也可以说是  复出赛
You know, something to start back with.
-让你重拾信心  -没错
- Get your confidence back. - That's it.
你得重整旗鼓
You've got to get your confidence back.
就这意思
That's all.
你爸想让萨尔做你的经纪人
Your dad wants Sal to manage you,
让我做教练
And he wants me to train you,
但有一个条件
But he'll only do it on one condition.
-不能再迁就那帮疯子  -没错
- No crazy time nonsense. - That's how it's got to be.
-没有迪奇和爱丽丝  -没有迪奇和爱丽丝
- No Dicky, no Alice. - No Dicky, no Alice.
我懂  我懂  我都明白
I get it. I get it. I'm good. I understand.
我很珍惜这次机会
Look, I appreciate the opportunity.
受不了那鬼扯的一套了  小米  无意冒犯  乔治
Can't take the bullshit, Mick. No offense, George.
没关系  我是说
None taken. I mean,
我去摆平他  大不了把他骟了
I'm going to be the one that gets his balls cut off anyway.
你们就笑吧
Yeah, you laugh.
-你个叛徒  -你这是干什么
- You traitor! - What are you doing?
你这又犯的什么神经病
What the hell's the matter with you?
我的天
Come on!
疼吗  疼死你才好
Did that hurt? I hope it hurt!
-萨尔・拉纳诺是个好人  -好人?
- Sal Lanano is a good man! - A good man?
-人家是正经的生意人  -正经的生意人?
- He's a legitimate businessman! For Christ sake. - Legitimate businessman?
-怎么了  -我的老天  知道那听上去像什么吗
- What? - Oh, my God, you know what that sounds like?
-他丫是个骗子  乔治  -他是出租车公司的老板
- He's a crook, George! - He owns a taxicab company!
-手底下有很多人  -天哪  他是个开出租的
- He's organized! - Oh, my God, he's a cab driver.
-他对拳击这行了如指掌吧  -没错
- He knows everything about boxing, right? - Yes.
放你娘的屁
I don't think so!
他是想把你儿子的钱一个子儿不剩全骗走
I think he's going to steal your son's money and rob him blind!
你怎么能这么想  你为什么非要这么想
Why would you think that? Why would you even think that?
-你就是不肯信任任何人  -我把人都看透了
- Why can't you trust anybody? - I know people.
乔治  我知道你嫌我没见识  可我了解人的心理
I know, George. You think I don't know anything. But I know people.
你可真是通情达理...
I know you know things...
那什么萨尔・拉那那还是拉粑粑的
And that Sal Lanana banana fucking thing...
我们不需要他
We don't need that in our lives!
孩子们跟着你根本赚不着钱
We haven't made one dollar with these kids.
你背叛了我  你背叛我
You betrayed me. You betrayed me.
我操  我背叛你个妹
Oh, bullshit, I betrayed you.
-总这么说有意思吗...  -他是个大骗子
- You're always have to say... - He's a fucking crook!
你想让米奇怎么办  迪奇还在监狱里
What's Micky supposed to do? Dicky's in jail.
我们没说教练的事  宝贝
We're not talking about his trainer, sweetheart.
我们在说谁该当经纪人  是你娘我
We're talking about his manager, that's me!
没错  可是妈  也许米奇该尝试些改变...
Yeah, but Mom, maybe Micky should try something different...
你是吃哪碗饭的  敢跟我在这顶嘴
What are you doing, opening your mouth in my kitchen?
你还欠我200块呢
You owe me $200.
我说了下周给你
I said I was going to pay you next week.
你给我闭上你的嘴
I don't want another word out of you.
你上个月就和我这么说
That was last month you told me two weeks.
你吃我的  住我的  欠我的钱  还胳膊肘往外拐
Do you take sides against me in my own house? You owe me money?
妈妈才是对米奇最好的  雪莉
Mom's been great to Micky, Sherri.
没错  谁能比妈妈更会照顾自己的儿子
Really, who's going to look after Micky better than his own mother?
都是夏琳那婊子惹的祸
It's that fucking girl, Charlene.
我们得去除掉她  妈妈
We've got to get rid of her, Mom.
得去除掉她
We've got to get rid of her.
都是夏琳闹的  她得滚蛋
It's that girl, Charlene. She's got to go.
你们要把夏琳搅进来吗
You're going to get Charlene involved in this?
你们是这意思吗
Is that what you're all telling me?
-是吗  -我知道她住哪
- Huh? - I know where she lives.
你们找她去干什么
What are you picking on her for?
她就住斯蒂文街的一栋黄色的楼里
She lives in that yellow house on Steven Street.
没错  屎黄色的
Yeah, the puke yellow.
我得跟米奇谈谈  我得亲自摆平这事
I'm going to talk to Micky. Sort this out for myself.
-没错  带着你的城管大队去吧  -咱们走
- Yeah, sure. You go handle it with your vigilantes.  - Go.
你大错特错了  爱丽丝
This is wrong, Alice!
-我来开  -都别挡道  快上车
- I got it. - Get out of my way! Get in the car.
快上来
Get in the car.
米奇  你在里面吗
Micky, are you in there?
就在二楼
Up in there on the second floor.
米奇
Micky!
你在哪呢
Where the hell are you, huh?
你在楼上吗  快下来
Are you up there? Come on down.
你在哪
Where are you?
天哪  米奇  你妈带着你的姐妹团来了
Holy shit, Micky. Your mother and your sisters are here.
不  不  别出去  求你了
No, no. Do not go out there, please.
不  我干嘛要躲着这些疯婆子
No, I'm not hiding from your crazy fucking family.
哎呦喂  瞧瞧
Well, well, well. Look at this.
瞧什么
Look at what?
为什么躲着我们  米奇
Why are you hiding from us, Micky?
-他没有  -谁跟你说话了
- He's not hiding. - I wasn't talking to you.
我跟我儿子说话呢
I was talking to my son.
-你站她后边干嘛  -我就在这呀
- What are you doing next to her? - I'm right here.
我谁都没躲  爱丽丝
I ain't hiding from nobody, Alice.
你和你爸那混账朋友拉纳诺一起没前途
Well you're not helping yourself with your father's scumbag friend, Lanano.
然后你想干嘛  把迪奇扔在一边吗
What are you going to do? Turn your back on Dicky next, huh?
我们只是想帮你成为世界冠军
All we ever wanted for you was to be world champion.
米奇不是小孩子了  他能为自己做主
Micky's a grown man. He can think for himself.
-闭你丫的嘴  -妖妇
- Shut your mouth. - Skank!
别再叫我妖妇
Don't call me skank.
小心我拔秃你的头发
I'll rip that nasty hair right out of your fucking head.
我是他的妈妈  也是他的经纪人
I'm his mother and his manager.
你不再是我的经纪人了
You're not my manager anymore.
我也不会等迪奇出狱  我耗不起这时间了
And I'm not waiting for Dicky, okay? I'm not getting any younger.
-那谁来照顾你呢  亲爱的  -我自己呀
- Who's going to look after you, sweetheart? - How about me?
我知道你不会懂  我有九个孩子
I know you don't understand it but I had nine kids,
你们每一个都是我的心头肉
and I love every one of you the same.
让他挨打  让他的手受伤  如果这就是你的爱
You've got a funny way of showing it, letting him get beat up,
-那他受不起  -臭婊子  -你疯了
- letting him get his hand broken. - Bastard. - You're crazy.
-臭婊子  -忘了我刚才说什么吗
- Bastard. - What did I just say to you?
放开她
Let her go.
操你妈
Fuck you!
操
Fuck!
都给我滚  快
Get the fuck out of here! Now!
-去死吧  夏琳  -米奇
- Fuck you, Charlene!  - Micky.
-妖妇  -有本事出来呀
- Skank! - I want them the fuck out of here.
-你死定了  -贱人
- You're fucking dead. - Fucking bitch!
盖尔  天哪  你鼻子怎么了
Gail! Oh, my God. What did she do to your nose?
咱们撤
Let's get the hell out of here.
这到底是怎么了  宝贝们  我不明白
What's happening to everybody? I don't understand, sweetheart.
沃德对阵赫尔南德兹
新罕布什尔州  汉普顿沙滩娱乐场
我的名字里多拼了个E
Why do you think I spell my name with an "E"? Because I don't.
-米奇・沃德  不是"米基"  -没人按电梯吗
- "No E" Micky Ward. - Hey, somebody push that button.
"爱尔兰人"
米奇・沃德
-咱们去哪  -去拳击场
- Where are we going? - To the ring.
在马路对面
The ring's across the street.
-拳击场在马路对面?  -是
- The ring's across the street? - Yeah.
是个小场地  那没更衣室
Smaller venue. They've got no dressing rooms over there.
这是你首场比赛  米奇  慢慢来
It's a starter, Micky. Just a starter.
你好
Hey.
好运
Good luck.
第四回合
太棒了  太棒了
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
沃德对阵马内蒂
沃德对阵柯林斯
迪克・埃克伦德  有人探视
Visit for Dick Eklund.
迪奇
Dicky!
听说你赢了好几场比赛  小米  真不错
Heard you won a bunch of fights, Mick. That's good.
我知道你知道我在干什么
I know you know what I'm doing.
爱丽丝什么的肯定都告诉你了
I'm sure Alice and everybody else told you.
我只想当面跟你说
I just wanted to tell you to your face myself.
我有了新的经纪人  麦基・奥基夫现在是我教练
I've got a new manager and Mickey O'Keefe's my trainer now.
一切都很好
It's going good.
是呀  他们说你下场对阿尔方索・桑切斯
Yeah. They've got you fighting Alfonso Sanchez.
-HBO台会转播  -觉得挺自豪吧
- On HBO. - Bet you're proud of that.
-当然了  -HBO就善于靠墨西哥式拳击捞钱  醒醒吧
- Fucking right. - HBO is the best at the Mexican fight. Wake up.
我没想到他们会在我身上下那么大本钱
I didn't think they were going to be invested in me.
-我的机会来了  我得抓住它  -别做梦了
- I've got a shot. I'm going to take it. - Wake up.
他们才不管你死活
They don't care if it kills you.
肯定是迈克・托马  他在利用你
Mike Toma did it. He's using you.
让桑切斯踩着你往上爬
Like a stepping stone for Sanchez.
-你怎么就不明白  -我明白
- Why don't you see? - Oh, I see.
没有伟大的迪克・埃克伦德在场边指导
How could I stand a chance without the great
我怎么可能赢呢  对吧
Dick Eklund in my corner, right?
当初就算我被穆金打死了  你也无动于衷吧
You didn't give a fuck if I got killed by Mungin,
如今你倒善心大发了
now, all of the sudden,
担心桑切斯会伤着我
you're worried Sanchez is going to hurt me?
为什么
Why?
坦白点吧  迪克  就因为你现在
Come on, Dick. Because you're stuck
身陷大狱而不再是瞩目的焦点
in here and can't be the center of attention no more?
-你就那么想出名吗  -这可是墨西哥式拳击
- You need it that bad? - It's a Mexican fight.
那老墨发起狠来就像头野驴  你知道吗
He fights you, hits like a fucking mule, all right?
15次连胜  你是真傻假傻?
Fifteen counts undefeated. You crazy?
那个开出租的白痴拉纳诺  他巴不得你死
And that taxicab idiot, Lanano? He went right for it.
他就是个纸老虎  利用你偷钱
He's a paper gangster. He's using you to steal money.
你为什么就不能闭上嘴为我高兴会
Why can't you just shut up and be happy for me?
过去十年  我一直荒废在你和爱丽丝
I've spent the last ten years
给我安排的坑爹的比赛中
of my life in bad fights set up by you and Alice.
如今我终于熬出点成绩
I've finally got a good thing going for me,
你就不为我感到一丁点的欣慰吗  为什么
and you can't be fucking happy for me? Why?
你有什么战术  你想怎么对付桑切斯
What's your plan? How are you going to fight Sanchez?
我不想谈这个
I ain't going to talk about that.
你的战术是什么
What's your plan?
-我不是来谈这个  -放屁  你就是
- I'm not here to talk about that. - Bullshit. Yes you are.
你到时候看比赛就知道了
You watch the fight and you'll see the plan.
我看不了  他们不让看
I can't watch it. They don't let us.
说那太你妈暴力  明白吗
It's too fucking violent, you know?
还有两分钟  迪奇
Two minutes, Dicky.
-他们给我们放什么傻逼吸毒纪录片  -迪奇
- They let us watch a stupid documentary about crack,  - Dicky.
却不让我看亲弟弟的拳击赛
but I can't watch my own brother fighting.
说呀  小米  你想怎么打
Hey, Mick. What is it?
你害怕了  你想不出战术所以无地自容?
You scared? You embarrassed because you don't even have a plan?
我是你哥哥  告诉我
I'm your brother. Just tell me.
不论我说什么你都会嘲笑我
You're going to shit on it no matter what I say.
怎么会呢  跟我说说
I'm not going to shit on it. Just tell me.
步步紧逼  中间回合开始右下击拳
Go toe-to-toe, overhand right in middle rounds.
那是他软肋
He's weak against overhand right.
-谁出的这主意  胖子奥基夫吗  -操你妈  迪奇
- Who came up with that? Fatty fuck O'Keefe? - Fuck you, Dicky.
他出击  你就躲  拖着他  直到他丧失斗志
You've got to run against this guy. Let him burn himself out.
贴紧他  懂吗  到他内侧去  注意脚下移动
Take it to the body, right? Get inside, switch stances
用假动作恍他  声东击西
like you're going to work his right. Hit him on the left.
你不是我  你也不可能成为我
You ain't me. Okay, you can't be me.
就因为你以前都是按你的意愿行事
You had a hard enough time being you when you had your fucking chance,
所以你才沦落到大狱里  好吧
and that's why you're in here, all right?
我要用我自己的方式击败桑切斯
I'll fight Sanchez the way I fight.
我就是在说你的方式  你个傻瓜
I'm talking about the way you fight, you moron!
-你知道我是对的  他知道  -是呀
- You know I'm right. He knows I'm right. - All right.
桑切斯对阵沃德
拉斯维加斯  托马斯&麦克体育中心
打右路
Blow to the right.
沃德入场  目前战绩  29胜  7负
Ward just in. 29 wins, 7 losses so far.
20次击倒对手
Twenty KOs.
刚J・B也指出  他自从回归拳坛后
He's been a little better since he refocused himself on the sport,
表现一直不错
as J.B. pointed out.
现在登场的是沃德的对手  来自墨西哥蒂华纳的
Now here's Ward's opponent, Alfonso Sanchez,
阿尔方索・桑切斯  战绩  16胜  15次击倒对手
out of Tijuana, Mexico. See the record, 16 wins, 15 KOs,
其中8次在第一局内击倒
8 first-round KOs.
这位是迈克・托马  此次比赛的发起人
There's Mike Toma, the promoter of the fight,
他在桑切斯身上投入不小
who has a lot invested in Sanchez.
称桑切斯是拳击界最有潜力的新星之一
He says that Sanchez is one of the most talented young prospects in the sport of boxing.
这可算是拳击史上最糟糕的比赛之一了
This is really one of the saddest kinds of fights in boxing.
米奇・沃德已经31岁了  他出来比赛就为了养家糊口
Micky Ward is 31 years old. He's here because he needs the money.
他正在挨打
He's taking a beating.
他真没必要在这挨拳头
My point is that he doesn't really have to sit here and take this beating.
-他该做些什么  -比如说?  让教练扔毛巾?
- He can do something about it. - Which is what?  Have his corner throw in the towel?
或是回击
Or fight back.
你可以看到他的力量  沃德被他打得步步后退
You can see his power. Every time he hits Ward, he backs him up.
除非裁判认为他撑不住了...
Unless the referee thinks he can't...
裁判该停止比赛
The referee should just stop this fight.
米奇肯定不想再继续下去了
We know that Micky doesn't want to be here.
不  他打得畏首畏尾  迪克
No, he's fighting scared, Dick.
一直躲闪  不回击
Running away, not hitting back.
天哪  这下肯定伤得不轻
Oh, Jesus. He's going to get hurt.
接着这么找死吧
Doing the same old shit.
从没看过这么惨的比赛
Never seen such an embarrassing performance.
是我告诉他那么做的  妈妈  他在按我说的做
He's doing what I told him, Mom. He's doing what I told him.
别担心  是我教他那样的
Don't worry about it. He's doing what I told him.
米奇・沃德只得...
Micky Ward showing nothing but...
你总躲什么  别再抱头乱窜了
What are you running around for? Stop running around.
闭你娘的嘴  萨尔  别说了
Shut the fuck up, Sal. Shut the fuck up!
我不知道你在干什么  米奇
I don't know what you're doing, Micky.
想谈谈吗
You want to fucking tell me?
我真不知道你想干什么
Because I don't know what you're doing.
我们已经输了五局了
We'd have lost all five rounds.
这就是你想要的吗
Is that what you want?
这太可怕了  太可怕了
This is dreadful, dreadful stuff.
一会告诉我是否还要继续  小米
You've got to show me something soon, Mick
否则我要终止比赛了
or I'm going to stop the fight.
他们要终止比赛了  米奇
They're going to stop the fight, Micky.
他是要贴进去  妈妈
He's got to go inside, Mom.
他要贴到对方身上  他懂的
He's got to take it to the body. He's got it.
不许终止比赛  用不着终止
Don't stop the fight. Don't stop it.
你得做点什么  宝贝  做点什么
You've got to do something, baby. You've got to do something.
试着按我说的做  米奇
Try what we talked about, Micky.
记得咱的战术吗  可你偏不照做
We had a plan, and you're not doing it.
去吧
Let's go.
米奇  你已经输了前五回合
All right, Micky. You've lost the first five rounds,
下一回合还会如此悲剧吗
what's the next strategy going to be?
桑切斯两记右直拳  三记左勾拳
Double right hand by Sanchez, then a triple left hook.
拳头如雨点般打在米奇・沃德脸上
Couple of the left hooks landed flush on the cheek of Micky Ward.
沃德紧紧贴住桑切斯
Ward tying Sanchez up.
米奇・沃德的表现十分奇怪
Very curious performance by Micky Ward.
沃德貌似想要用一记重拳
Ward seems to be trying to land
警告桑切斯自己不是好惹的...
one big shot to either change Sanchez's mind...
他双臂的防御开始松懈
And he's beginning to open up,
他想趁机靠近沃德
taking advantage of opportunities to get close to Ward
挥拳猛击这个
and throw against a fighter
并不出拳进行自卫的拳击手
who is not defending himself by punching.
桑切斯想要终结这场比赛
Sanchez is going to try to end this fight.
你干什么呢  加油
What are you doing? Come on.
加油
Come on!
他被一记上钩拳击倒了
He's down on an uppercut.
一记精准的左勾拳直击要害
Nicely thrown left uppercut inside.
很精彩  沃德刚挥出一记很不错的右拳
Very good. And right after Ward threw a pretty good right hand.
小米  你还好吗
Mick, you all right?
这场比赛不该再进行下去了
This is a fight that should be stopped.
加油  头部  身体  头部连击
Come on, head, body, head.
-这根本不是专业竞技  -我就是这意思
- This is not professional. - That's exactly what I'm saying.
给钱我也不愿意看这样的比赛
I sure wish they paid me to watch this.
加油  小米  头部  身体  头部连击
Come on, Mick! Head, body, head.
沃德作出了一记漂亮的身体攻击
That was a good body shot by Ward.
-或许他要展开反击  -我说的是他的身体攻击
- Maybe he'll turn it around. - I'm talking about his body shot.
桑切斯被那拳击倒了  噢  天啊
Sanchez dropped by that shot! Oh, my God!
这拳太漂亮了
What a punch!
这是你所见过的最不可思议的击倒
The most unlikely knockout you have ever seen!
那是一记肾击
That is a kidney shot.
这种肾击并没有那么猛烈
The kind of kidney shot that's not as severe...
我还是没法相信刚才看到的那一幕
I still don't believe what I just saw!
米奇  米奇  米奇
Micky! Micky! Micky!
米奇赢了
Micky won!
现在看来  米奇・沃德似乎用他那
Now did Micky Ward just make
卓越不群的拳击战术把我们都给耍了
idiots of us all with a spectacular piece of strategy?
-再看一遍  -太惊人了
- Take another look. - Amazing.
这真是来自洛厄尔的米奇・沃德
A big win in the career of
拳击生涯中一次至关重要的胜利
Micky Ward of Lowell, Mass.
米奇・沃德的双拳创造了一次令人难以置信的胜利
Unbelievable defeat at the hands of Micky Ward,
他在比赛中
who had all but given
居然直接放弃了前六轮
away the first half dozen rounds in the bout.
我想米奇的这种打法是因为
I think what Micky did was he
他认准了他的身体攻击会收到奇效
recognized that he'd hurt the guy with the body shot.
米奇这名选手的打法
Micky's a better fighter than
比仅仅一味硬拼要强的多
that to not be running from that guy like that.
大逆转
Theater of the unexpected.
你永远不知道会发生什么  对吧
Hey, you never know what can happen, right?
在拳击场上决不能放弃  对吧  决不能放弃
Never give up in this game, right? Never give up.
千真万确  朋友们
You can't make it up, folks.
你们知道米奇刚才说了什么吗
You know what Micky just said?
他说在拳击场上  你决不能放弃
He said you can't give up in this game.
可能米奇当时听到我说他该停止这场比赛
Well maybe Micky Ward heard me say he should stop this fight,
-于是他站出来阻止了  -没错
- and he went out and stopped it. - Yeah.
我真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
我在下面看着
I'm looking over and I'm
我跟他们一样  心里想着
thinking to myself like they were thinking:
这比赛完了
This thing is over.
可我告诉你  甚至是那些解说
But I tell you what. Even look at the commentators.
在击倒倒数结束之前
They started to take their
他们都把耳机摘下来了
headsets off before he was even counted out.
-他们都想走了  -小米
- They just wanted to get out of there. - Mick. Mick...
我刚又跟迈克・托马谈了谈
I just spoke to Mike Toma again
他跟我说了些很有意思的事
and he just told me something very interesting.
他刚告诉我  要是桑切斯今晚赢了
He just told me, had Sanchez won tonight,
他就能参加拳王争霸赛
he would have gotten the title shot.
-老天啊  那太棒了  -怎么了  这有什么棒
- Holy Christ, that's beautiful. - Why? Why is that beautiful?
-拳王争霸赛  -这下米奇能参加了
- A title shot. - Micky gets the shot.
你确定吗
Are you sure about that?
你得把这事弄清楚了
You've got to be very clear about this,
-这可关系到我儿子的将来  -我刚跟那人谈过
- because this is my kid's future. - I just spoke to the guy.
-迈克  来  告诉他们  -恭喜
- Mike, come here. Look, tell these guys. - Hey. Congratulations.
-谢谢  -再也不是垫脚石了
- Thank you. - Not a stepping stone anymore.
我就知道你有这种天分  多么伟大的战术
I always knew you had the talent. That was a hell of a strategy,
不断消耗他的体能  然后一记身体攻击终结
wearing him down like that and taking it to the body.
我在这行干了三十年
Thirty years in the business,
还从没见过这样的击倒
I've never seen a knockout like that.
评论员莫什特都在准备给你写讣告了
Larry Merchant was writing your
然而桑切斯像吃了枪子一样倒了下来
obituary and Sanchez drops like he was shot with a gun.
你从哪儿学的这招
Where did you get that?
那是我哥哥教我的第一课
That's the first thing my brother taught me.
敲打他们的头  再猛捣他们的身体
Tap them to the head, dig into the body.
-真是一记漂亮的身体攻击  -谢谢
- That's a hell of a body shot. - Thank you.
准备好参加拳王争霸赛了吗
You ready for a title shot?
-准备好了  -准备好了
- Yes! - Yes!
我刚说的就是这个
That's what I was talking about.
他准备好了  你准备好了  对吧
He's ready. You're ready, aren't you?
伦敦的拳王谢伊・奈里
Shea Neary in London for the title!
你说真的吗  我们得庆祝一下
Are you kidding me? We've got some celebrating to do.
-没错  我也这么想  -太感谢你了
- Yeah, I think so. - Thank you so much.
你将会成为伟大的拳王  孩子
You're going to have a great champion, my boy.
那是你哥哥的梦想
It's what your brother would have always wanted.
他甚至没法到场
He's not even going to be there.
-嘿  -爸爸
- Hey! - Daddy!
-嘿  小伙子  -爸爸  爸爸
- Hey there, buddy. - Daddy, Daddy!
见到你真好
Good to see you! Oh!
抱得好  抱得好
That's a good hug! That's a good hug! Oh yeah!
-宝贝  -妈妈
- Sweetheart! - Hi, Mom.
你看起来真好
Oh, you look so good.
天啊
Oh, my God.
-你的牙真干净  -是吧  看我这口牙
- You have clean teeth. - I do! Look at my teeth!
我换了新牙  都是新的
I got new teeth. Everything.
你觉得我看起来怎么样
How do you think I look?
-很好  -是吗
- Good. - Yeah?
-你要带上我吗  -不
- Are you going to carry me? - No.
还有蛋糕  冰淇淋
And more cake. Ice cream...
-冰淇淋加蛋糕  -冰淇淋加蛋糕蛋糕蛋糕
- Ice cream with cake. - Ice cream with cake and cake and cake.
冰淇淋蛋糕蛋糕  冰淇淋蛋糕蛋糕
Ice cream, cake and cake. Ice cream, cake and cake.
呱呱
Quacker!
妈
Mom.
-他们给你换了新牙  -是啊
- They gave you some new teeth, huh? - Yeah.
乔治  你怎么出来了
Hey, George. They let you out of the house now?
把他放出来了吗  妈
Run him out of the house, Mom?
听着  来认识一下萨尔・拉纳诺
Hey, look. I want you to meet Sal Lanano.
你好吗  迪奇
How you doing, Dicky?
咱们训练吧  好吗
Let's spar, huh?
你好  夏琳
Hi, Charlene.
-欢迎回来  -嘘  得给他个惊喜
- Welcome back! - Shh! It's supposed to be a surprise!
我要迟到了
I'm running late.
小米  我简直难以形容
Mick, I can't even tell you.
重新回到这间难闻的更衣室
Being back in this smelly-ass locker room...
经历了这一切  终于能回来跟你一起
Getting back with you is what got me through.
你看起来不错  眼睛更清澈了
You look good. Your eyes are clear.
爱丽丝说入狱对我来说或许是件好事
Alice says prison might have been the best thing for me.
让我更纯净了  把我这里洗干净了
It got me clean. Got me clear up here.
那真好  迪克
It's a beautiful thing, Dick.
我得跟你说件事
I've got to talk to you about something.
还是那个老柜子
The old locker, huh?
我跟他们保证不再跟你一起干了
I made a promise to them I wouldn't work with you again.
我只能这样  发生了那么多事  对不起
I had to, after everything that happened. I'm sorry.
你说真的吗
You sticking to that?
我很高兴你回来了
I'm glad you're back.
你看起来很好
You look good.
我不知道还能说些什么
I don't know what else to say.
-小米  你他妈开玩笑吧  -没有
- Mick, you fucking kidding me? - No, I'm not.
-米奇  -米奇  过来
- Hey, Micky. - Micky, come on in.
你们太吵了  还是省着回家庆祝吧  拜托
You're too loud. You've got to do this at home, please.
-你说什么呢  -妈  拜托
- What are you talking about? - Mom, please.
好吧  姑娘们  咱们收起来
All right, girls. Let's pack it up.
-为什么  -把它收起来
- Why? - Let's get it put away.
要是米奇想这样  我们就收起来
If that's what Micky wants, we're going to put it away.
-哥哥来了  -迪奇
- There's your brother. - Dicky!
大家好  大家好
Hey there. Hey there.
真好  真不错
It's nice. It's nice.
-我们花了两个星期  -雪莉  别哭了
- Been working on it for two weeks. - Hey, Sherri, come on. Stop.
好吧  姑娘们  来吧  咱们回家
All right, girls, come on. Let's go home.
显然  现在不适合弄这个
It's not the time to do this, obviously.
-怎么了  -我们不能一起干了
- What's going on? - We ain't going to work together.
他们不想让我和他一起
They don't want me to work with him.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
这可不对
That's not right.
要不是迪奇  米奇可赢不了桑切斯
Micky never would have won Sanchez without Dicky.
你他妈瞎说什么  给我收回去
That's fucking bullshit! Take it back!
-别他妈这么跟我妈说话  -操你妈的
- Don't you fucking talk to my mother like that. - Fuck you!
你怎么不问问米奇
Why don't you ask Micky?
我们要训练了  让他们走
We're going to train. They've got to go.
让他们走  小米  拜托了
They've got to go, Mick. Come on.
-你还好吗  -问他  乔治
- You all right? - Ask him, George.
问问他要不是他哥哥  他能赢桑切斯吗
Ask him if he would have won Sanchez without his brother.
对  要不是迪奇我赢不了桑切斯
No, I wouldn't have won Sanchez if it wasn't for Dicky.
-你怎么能当着奥基夫这么说  -因为事实如此
- How can you say that to O'Keefe? - Because it's true.
我试着用我们的战术
I went in with our game plan and it
可没奏效  我就重新用迪奇教我的打法
wasn't working so I went back to what I learned with Dicky.
要不是你我也赢不了  奥基夫  行吗
And I wouldn't have won without you, either, O'Keefe, okay?
你也知道  我们刻苦训练  你让我准备充分
I mean, you know that. We worked hard. You got me ready.
你的信心和斗志都来自奥基夫
You got your confidence and your focus from O'Keefe,
来自萨尔  父亲  还有我
and from Sal, and from your father, and from me.
-迪奇是个废物  -喂
- Dicky is a junk bag. - Hey!
他就是个废物
He's a junk bag!
-操你妈的  夏琳  -操你妈的
- Fuck you, Charlene. - Oh, fuck you!
我已经清醒了
I'm sober.
是吗  我觉得你既然已经出来了
Oh, yeah. And I'm sure you're going
肯定又会找借口去弄那玩意
to need something for something now that you're out.
-"我的背不行了"  -操你妈的
- "Oh, my back! Oh, my back!" - Fuck you!
-为什么你总是找我的茬  -操你妈的
- What are you always picking on me for, huh? - No, fuck you!
那奥基夫怎么说  我们是一条船上的
And what about O'Keefe? We're in the same boat.
我们一起工作过吧  奥基夫  你跟我
One day at a fucking time, right, O'Keefe? You and me.
现在他在这怎么就行了
It's all right for him to be here?
为什么问题都他妈出在我身上
Why am I the fucking problem?
-我是他的亲人  他的家人  -你自己就是个问题
- I'm his blood! I'm his family! - You're the problem!
我才是拳击手  好吗  不是你  不是你  也不是你
I'm the one fighting, okay? Not you, not you, and not you.
-我知道我需要什么  -你需要迪奇吗
- I know what I need. - And you need Dicky?
我想让迪奇回来
I want Dicky back.
我也要你  夏琳  我也要奥基夫
And I want you, Charlene, and I want O'Keefe.
我要我的家人  这有什么问题
I want my family. What's wrong with that?
-这可不是我们说好的  宝贝  -她说得对  米奇
- Not the deal we made, baby. - She's right, Micky.
-这不是我们说好的  -不是我们说好的
- That's not the deal. - It wasn't the deal.
拜托  你不能这么对我们
Come on, you can't do this to us.
你现在说话跟他们一样了
You sound like them now.
-我说话跟他们一样  -对  你说话跟他们一样
- I sound like them now? - Yeah, you sound like them.
我们说话跟他们一样
We sound like them?
你不能这么对我们  你不能这么对我们
You can't do this to us. You can't do this to us.
你说话跟他们一样
You sound like them.
你他妈真该好好听听你在说什么
You should fucking listen to yourself.
你说话跟他们一样  一模一样
You sound like them, just like them.
或许这才是你的归宿
Maybe this is where you belong.
-你就是这么爱他的吗  -夏琳
- That's the way you love him? - Charlene!
-拜托  -你想要你哥哥  自求多福吧
- Come on! - You want your brother? Good luck.
-奥基夫  拜托  -米奇
- O'Keefe, come on... - Micky.
米奇
Micky...
好了  事出必有因
Come on, everything happens for a reason.
说不定这样对大家都好
You know, maybe it's for the best.
老天自有公道
God has a plan.
想跟你哥哥练练吗
Want to spar with your brother?
迪克・埃克伦德  洛厄尔的骄傲
Dick Eklund, Pride of Lowell.
那些年都是这么练的吧
Watching that for years, huh?
你他妈这是干什么
Whoa, hey, what the hell are you doing?
-米奇  我的天哪  -爸爸  爸爸
- Micky, for crying out loud! - Daddy, Daddy, Daddy!
把那孩子带出去
Take that baby out of here.
十分钟前我就跟你说了把他带走
I told you take him away ten minutes ago!
宝贝  你还好吗  你的背怎么样了
Sweetheart, are you all right? You okay? Your back?
你干什么呢  你出什么毛病了
What are you doing? What's the matter with you?
这次能为了我吗  爱丽丝
Will it be my fight, Alice? Huh?
就一次  就这么一次  不为了迪奇
Just once? Maybe just this one time, not for Dicky?
我知道你觉得现在他回来了
I know you think he's coming back,
可他都四十了
but he's forty years old and he
他嘴里连他妈一颗自己的牙都没有
doesn't have a tooth in his head that's his fucking own.
先让你弟弟说两句  行吗
Let your brother talk for a minute here, all right?
你想说什么  宝贝
What are you saying, sweetheart?
再不闭嘴我打爆你的头  迪奇
Shut up before I bust your fucking head open, Dicky.
你想怎么着
What are you going to do?
你他妈想让我打爆你的头吗
You want me to bust your fucking head open?
拜托  拜托  乔治
Come on! Come on! George!
-求求你们  -迪奇
- Please! Please! - Dicky!
你想说什么  宝贝  告诉我
What are you saying, sweetheart? Tell me what you're saying.
这该是我的比赛
This is supposed to be my fight.
-这是我成为拳王的机会  -是你的比赛
- This is my shot at a title. - It is your fight.
我再也不会有这样的机会了
I won't get another one after this.
我自私吗  我有没有一直在叫自己的名字
Am I being selfish? Am I saying "Micky! Micky! Micky!"?
要是我自私  对不起
Because you know what? If I am, I'm sorry.
我一直以为我能为了冠军而奋斗
I thought I was fighting for the championship.
我还以为你也是我妈妈
And I thought you were my mother, too.
我是你妈妈
I am your mother.
小米  对不起  我不知道你会这么想  好吗
Mick, I'm sorry. I had no idea you felt like that, all right?
要是我做错了什么  我会改的
If I made mistakes, I'm going to be better.
我不想伤害你  真对不起
I don't want to hurt you. I am so sorry.
对不起
I'm sorry.
迪奇  你陪着他
Dicky! Stay with him.
迪奇
Dicky!
-迪奇  -我有事要做
- Dicky! - Got to do something.
迪奇  等会  拜托
Dicky, wait. Come on.
米奇需要你  我也需要你
Micky wants you. I want you.
我有事要做
I've got to do something.
我知道你是什么意思  别这样
I know what that means. Don't do this!
"洛厄尔的骄傲"回来了
吉姆
Hey, Jim.
-斯玛特  -迪奇
- Smart. - Hey, Dicky.
迪奇回来了
Hey, Dicky's back!
迪奇
Dicky!
-看看你  -看看这小子
- Look at you! - Look at my boy, huh?
过来
Come over here.
你看起来不错  欢迎回来
You look good. Welcome back.
-是啊  你看起来不错  -看起来真好
- Yeah, you're looking good. - You look great.
见到你真好
Good to see you.
-欢迎回家  -嗨  宝贝
- Welcome home. - Hi, honey.
还好吗  哥们  你看起来不错
What's up, man? You're looking good.
要不要上去坐坐
So, want to head up there?
迪奇回来了
Dicky's back!
上楼去  坐一会儿
Go upstairs, take a while, huh?
-给你庆祝一下  宝贝  -回来吧
- Throw a little party for you, babe. - Hey, come back!
他这是搞什么鬼
What the hell was that?
夏琳  我是迪奇
Charlene, it's Dicky.
滚远点  人渣
Get off my porch, you piece of shit.
你他妈的还有脸来我家
How fucking dare you come?
滚你妈的
Cock sucker!
王八蛋
Fucking boy!
垃圾
Fucking ass!
烂货
Fucking sick!
迪奇你个傻逼  给我滚远点
You're a fucking asshole, Dicky. I want you off my fucking porch.
你他妈怎么不下来
Huh? Why don't you just
让我们谈一谈
fucking come down here and talk to me, huh?
你这混蛋居然敢来我家
You're such an asshole, coming to my fucking house.
-还敢站在我家门口瞎喊  -对不起
- You piece of shit, standing on my porch! - Sorry, sorry.
像你这么对着大街喊叫
It's not fucking ladylike to
不太好吧
be shouting in the street like this, all right?
-你这混蛋还敢来  -求你了
- You're such a fucking cock sucker, coming over here. - Please!
-你以为我在乎吗  -求你了  下来吧
- Oh yeah? You think I fucking care? - Come on. Just fucking...
滚远点  迪奇
Get off my fucking porch, Dicky.
那是什么狗  西班牙长耳猎犬吗
What kind of dog is that? Is that a cocker spaniel?
我知道你受不了我
All right, I know you can't fucking stand me.
是吗  你也知道啊
Really, what makes you say that?
我告诉你件事
I got news for you, all right?
我弟弟爱着你
My brother loves you,
你不能因为我  就这么走了
and you can't just run away because of me.
你不能这么对他
He don't deserve that, all right?
如果你想我走  那我就走
So I will quit if you want me to quit.
-扯什么淡  -我说真的
- You're full of shit. - I swear to God.
如果你肯回来  我就退出
I will quit if it means you'll come back, all right?
但拜托你好好想想
But I want you to think about something.
米奇有机会做成我从未做过的事
Micky has a chance to do something that I never did,
我这辈子从没做过的事
that in my time, I never had.
可不是  我当时可打败了苏格・雷
Oh... "Yeah, my big chance
我他妈的真了不起
was with Sugar Ray Leonard. I'm so great."
我可是洛厄尔的骄傲
"I'm the Pride of fucking Lowell.
没错  我打败了苏格・雷
Oh yeah, I fought Sugar Ray Leonard."
-我都知道  -我来是想和你改变这一切
- I've heard it. - I came to make things right with you.
好  那就开始吧  首先
Okay, let's make things right. Number one:
你没有击倒苏格・雷  是他自己绊倒的
You didn't knock down Sugar Ray Leonard. He tripped.
我当时就在拳台上
I was in the ring. Don't you
难道我不知道是怎么回事吗
think I know what really fucking happened that day?
-你的生活成功吗  -我喜欢我的生活
- What have you ever done with your life? - I like my life.
你都有过什么成就
Yeah? What have you ever done with it?
我喜欢我现在的生活  迪奇
I like my life now, Dicky.
你有没有过什么成就
What have you ever done with your life?
你大学辍学  夏琳
You're a college dropout, Charlene.
只是个酒吧女  你的生活烂透了
You're just a little bar girl. Your life sucks.
好吧
All right.
我酗酒  还在很多酒吧工作过
I drink too much. I worked in a lot of bars.
我毁掉了无数机会
And I ruined a lot of opportunities,
但我正在努力改变
but I'm trying to do better here.
-米奇也是  -我也是
- So is Micky. - So am I.
你知道他需要我  我知道他也需要你
And he needs me, you heard him. And I know he needs you.
你胳膊上那什么玩意
What is that blue shit on your arm?
蛋糕的糖霜
It's icing.
好吧
Okay.
到时在米奇的教练席上再见  不然就见鬼去吧
I'll see you in Micky's corner. Otherwise, go fuck yourself.
-一言为定  -一言为定
- It's a deal. - All right, it's a deal.
我们帮你都说好了  问她吧
We worked it out for you. Ask her.
好吧  现在去把奥基夫找回来
Good. Go get O'Keefe back, too.
我会的
I will.
小米
Hey, Mick.
你觉得我击倒了苏格・雷吗
Do you think I knocked down Sugar Ray Leonard?
你坚持了十回合  能打伤他已经很棒了
You went ten rounds. One of the best to do anything to hurt him.
你是我的偶像
You're my hero.
我曾经是
I was.
曾经是
I was...
-对不起  -真的吗
- I'm sorry. - Yeah?
沃德对阵奈里
伦敦  世界拳击联盟次中量级
楼下有个新闻发布会
There's a press conference downstairs.
-走吧  -伙计们
- Come on. Let's go. - Guys...
奈里  146磅
Neary, Ten stone, six pounds.
沃德  146磅
Ward, Ten stone, six pounds.
米奇・沃德  我们有问题要问
Hey, Micky. Micky Ward! We have a question over here.
你是如何训练的
How have you been training?
没什么特别  刻苦训练而已
I train. I train hard.
谢伊二十二战全胜  从未被击倒过
Shea's 22 in 0. Never been knocked down.
明天就不是喽
Well that's going to change tomorrow.
我们其实期待着更强大的对手
In fact we expected a much better fighter.
我很高兴有机会参加这次比赛
I'm just grateful to be here and
谢谢你们的提问
have the opportunity. Thank you, guys, for the shot.
谢伊  你最喜欢哪个拳击手
Shea, who do you respect as a fighter?
下一场你打算和谁较量
And who would you like to fight next?
明天我会踩着米奇・沃德继续前进
I plan on moving right through Micky Ward tomorrow,
与其他更伟大的选手比赛  比如加蒂
moving on to other big fighters, like Gatti.
加蒂和我会进行一场伟大的比赛
I believe Gatti and I would make a great match.
女士们先生们  这里是世界拳击联盟
And now, ladies and gentlemen, twelve rounds of boxing
十二回合次中量级冠军赛
for the WBU Welterweight Championship of the World!
别理他们  小米
Don't listen to them, Mick.
下面进场的是来自马萨诸塞州
And there is Micky Ward of Lowell,
洛厄尔的米奇・沃德
Massachusetts entering the ring.
这是他第一次在美国之外比赛
It's his first fight outside the United States.
米奇・沃德  三十胜七负
Micky Ward, 30 wins, 7 losses....
他最近战绩不错  二十次击倒对手
He's back and better, recently. Twenty KOs.
沃德在等待他的对手  谢伊・奈里
And now Ward awaits his opponent, Shea Neary.
奈里自称欧洲的阿图罗・加蒂
Neary regards himself as the European Arturo Gatti,
这说明他是个注重进攻的选手
meaning that he is a head-on high-contact fighter
他每回合出拳达七十次
who throws seventy punches per round.
奈里来自利物浦
Neary is from Liverpool
所以他今晚会有众多的拥簇
and should have a huge following here tonight.
伴随着麦洪的《狂欢》
Accompanied by "Paint the Town Red" By the Mahone.
奈里是当下次中量级世界冠军
Neary is the current Welterweight Champion of the World.
他是个非常厉害的年轻选手
He is a very tough young man.
他无比专注  像斯巴达勇士一样生活
Beyond dedicated. Lives a spartan existence.
据他的赞助人称
And according to his promoters,
他只做这几件事  吃  喝  思考
there's nothing but eat, drink, think,
和梦想自己的拳击之路
fantasize and dream of fighting.
谢伊・奈里的战绩是二十二战全胜
Shea Neary has had 22 professional fights and won them all.
十七次击倒对手
Seventeen KOs.
铃声响了再开始  两位请握手
Start when you hear the bell. Shake hands.
你们两个  握手
Both of you. Shake hands.
两个人站在拳台中间
As close as we just saw them
头顶头相互较劲
in the middle of the ring, forehead to forehead.
这就是我们所一直
That's how close we expect them
期待的比赛气氛
to be for as long as this fight goes on.
沃德远渡重洋来到这  不会那么轻松
Ward is a long ways from home. Don't coast in a foreign country.
对于沃德来说  最大的挑战就是
Well, the big challenge for Ward is
摆脱旧习惯  迅速进入比赛
to get off to a faster start than is customary for him.
米奇・沃德在大赛中一向很慢热
Micky Ward a notoriously slow starter in big fights.
谢伊・奈里则是个急性子
Shea Neary an ultra-fast starter.
问题有待于第一回合
And that's the question that
才能揭晓  比赛要开始了
hovers over round one. Get ready for the fight.
谢伊・奈里已经把他逼至场边
Already Shea Neary starts taking it to him on the ropes.
奈里开始击打身体  这可是沃德的强项
And Neary going to the body, which is Ward's specialty.
奈里击打沃德的身体
Neary bangs Ward to the body.
然后奈里来了个漂亮的上勾拳
And a big uppercut by Neary.
奈里以一个漂亮的左刺拳领先
Neary leads off with a good left jab.
不断用刺拳破坏对手的防御
Keeps opponents off balance, jabbing here and there.
奈里一记漂亮的左勾拳击中了沃德
That was a good left hook by Neary as he stepped in on Ward.
奈里在这个距离进攻
Ward not able to deal with him
使得沃德有些被动
very well when Neary stands at range like this.
-加油  -就是这样  打他
- Come on! - That's it! Get him!
这对米奇・沃德来说有些艰难
My, is it tough for Micky Ward.
奈里不断用右拳击打沃德的身体
Neary digging his own right hand to the body.
近距离不断地击打
They trade shots at close range.
沃德试图反击
Ward is trying to match Neary blow-for-blow,
奈里重新开始进攻了
and now Neary starts to come
这回合进入最后三十秒
on and take the last thirty seconds to the round.
-这下可够受  -停
- How about that! - Break!
真是无比凶猛的一分钟啊
Tremendous barrage in the first minute.
瞧瞧这个  难以置信
Just look at this. Unbelievable.
多精彩的一回合
What a great round one!
沃德需要跟上比赛节奏
Ward is going to have to pick up the tempo
重振旗鼓  进行反击
and beat him with volumes of punching.
奈里无疑更棒
No doubt Neary is a better boxer.
在上一回合奈里挥出了四记重击
Four hard right hands Neary has belted in the last minute.
他比沃德更快  更果断地进攻
Quicker than Ward, more assertive than Ward.
对于自己的目标非常肯定
Surer of what he wants to do.
他们站在场中相持着
They're standing and trading shots at the center of the ring.
对于沃德现在的情况
Ward's going to have to step
他需要更加努力
it up a little bit more than he is right now.
米奇・沃德的教练组
Micky Ward's corner taking
真得好好研究一下现在的情况
a really deep look at what's going on now,
他的亲友团也希望他能更加努力
and his family at ringside well aware he's stepping up in class.
沃德需要更有侵略性
Ward has to got to be more aggressive.
他不能被动地等着对手犯错
He can't just try to wait until everything is perfect.
随着比赛的进行米奇・沃德会越来越悲观
Despondence over Micky Ward is increasing as the fight goes on
因为他的计划正确  他也在执行它
because his plan was the right one and he's executing it.
如此多的击打让奈里占据着主动
Punches like these make it seem that it's now Neary's fight.
沃德还从没有和奈里
Ward hasn't been in this
这种强壮的对手比赛过
kind of war with as strong a fighter as Neary.
他们在尝试用一拳打击对方
They are trying to hurt each other with only punches.
他们了解了对方的意图
They've tested each other's will,
现在在试探对方的技巧
now they're testing each other's skill.
沃德被奈里一记右交叉拳搞得手忙脚乱
And Ward fumbled there by a right cross from Neary.
沃德受伤了  他的步伐乱了
Ward hurting now, his legs are gone.
奈里打算终结掉米奇
Neary goes to the body as he tries to finish Micky.
奈里猛烈地进攻着
Vicious body shots from Neary.
而沃德甚至没想从围绳上离开
And Ward doesn't even try to move off the ropes.
我看他是不能吧  杰夫
I don't know if he can, Jeff.
他在等着奈里把他打出去
He's waiting for Neary to punch himself out.
米奇・沃德倒地了  他可能要出局了
Down goes Micky Ward, and he may be out.
站起来  加油
Come on, that's it!
好样的
That's my boy!
向前  向前  加油
Forward! Forward! Come on!
-沃德的脚步完全乱了  -废物  滚回美国吧
- Ward is out on his feet! - Loser! Go back to America!
这就是米奇・沃德的终结了吧
This could be it for Micky Ward.
迪奇  让他坐下  凳子他妈在哪
Dicky, get him a fucking stool! Where's the stool?
滚一边去  夏琳
Charlene, will you get the fuck out of here with your high heels?
沃德的哥哥在帮他恢复步伐
His brother's got Ward jumping to wake up his legs.
这么做是对的
I think this could be
这是沃德最后的胜机
Ward's last chance to turn this fight around.
这里是米奇沃德对阵
It's Micky Ward against the
出拳凶狠利落的谢伊・奈里
aggressiveness and clean punching of Shea Neary.
如果不好好防御  真的会受伤
If you don't have your defense up you can really get hurt.
米奇・沃德陷入了困境
He's making it very difficult for Micky Ward.
奈里看来不打算把金腰带交给他
I don't think he's going to give it to him, at this rate.
现在是生死存亡的时刻
This is a survival move.
你难道想像我一样  只能打败苏格・雷吗
Are you like me? Huh? Just good enough to fight Sugar Ray?
我从没得过冠军  你得超过我
I never had to win, did I? You've got to do more than that.
你要赢得冠军  为你  为我  为了洛厄尔
You've got to win a title. For you, for me, for Lowell.
这是你的机会  你得好好抓牢
This is your time, all right? You take it.
我也曾有过  但我搞砸了  你绝不能失败
I had my time, and I blew it. You don't have to, all right?
现在给我站起来  把你所有压抑的愤怒
Now fucking get out there. Bring that fucking anger.
把这么多年来所有的愤怒与不顺
All the shit you've been through over the fucking years,
全部发泄到拳台上
put it in the ring right now.
这是你的比赛  你的舞台
This is yours. This is fucking yours.
-好  -记住  头部  身体  头部连击
- Okay. - Fucking head, body, head, body.
-你说一遍  -头部  身体  头部连击
- Say it back to me. - Head, body, head, body.
你能做到  别他妈地贴在围绳上
You can do it. Stay off the fucking ropes.
如果我是米奇・沃德的教练
If I'm in Micky Ward's corner tonight,
我在想  如果他在这回合
I'm thinking if he doesn't
再不进攻
pick things up this round and get going,
他可能就没有机会了
he'll just get totally wiped out.
离开围绳  离开围绳  小米
Get off the ropes! Get off the ropes, Mick!
又是这样  沃德贴着围绳任由奈里进攻
Once again, Ward against the ropes as Neary is free to attack.
你在干什么  加油  小米
What are you doing? Come on, Mick...
有时候你要是想赢
Sometimes if you want to win,
就得去尝试一些没做过的事
you've got to be something that you're not.
离开他妈的围绳  这样不行
Off the fucking rope, man! That ain't it!
奈里继续着进攻
Neary continues to pound away.
别站着不动  这是你的比赛  米奇
Don't take no abuse! This is your time, Micky!
这都是为了你
It's all for you!
-奈里两击不中  -就是这样  就是这样
- Two big misses by Neary. - That's it! That's it!
沃德好像找回了节奏
Ward seemingly getting his legs back.
沃德压迫着奈里  不断地进攻
Now he backs Neary up. Ward trades his way back.
沃德在点头  好像在说  来吧
Ward nods as if to say "Come on!".
来吧  干上一架
"Come on, let's fight!"
越来越接近奈里的胸部
Closer and closer to Neary's ribcage.
现在米奇・沃德掌控了比赛
This is becoming Micky Ward's fight.
一记左勾拳  又一记上勾拳
And a left hook to the body, and an uppercut lands,
现在他正压迫着奈里
and now he backs Neary up.
沃德朝着奈里的身体给了一拳
Ward hits Neary with a body shot.
四记左勾拳
Four left hooks in the body.
奈里倒地了  二十三场职业比赛的第一次
Neary on his butt, first time in 23 professional fights
谢伊・奈里被击倒了
that Shea Neary has gone down.
就是这样  就是这样  米奇
This is it! This is it, Micky!
本回合还剩二十三秒
23 seconds remain in this
米奇现在胜利在望
round as Micky now wipes off Neary's gloves.
沃德击中一记左勾拳  米奇・沃德不断进攻
Ward lands a huge left hook as Micky Ward works away.
连续的左勾拳  又一记上勾拳
Blows to the body with the left hook. There's the uppercut again!
比赛结束
Gonna stop it right there.
米奇・沃德在第八回合以技术性击倒获胜
"Irish" Micky Ward with a big eighth-round TKO!
他又做到了  他又做到了
He's done it again. He's done it again.
米奇・沃德又艰难地赢得了一场大胜
They grinding gutting Micky Ward pulls out another big victory.
你是世界冠军
You're the champion of the world,
小米  你他妈的是世界冠军
Mick! You're the fucking champion of the world!
你他妈真的做到了
You fucking did it!
我儿子是世界冠军
My boy's the champion of the world!
我爱你
I love you!
镇里的人总说你是个拳击手
This town always said you're a fucking boxer, right?
你觉得这一文不值
You thought it's a piece of shit.
-他又让洛厄尔出了名  -是我们
- He put Lowell back on the map, you know. - We did.
-我告诉你  等等  -是我们
- I tell you. No, hold on. - We.
谁是曾经的"洛厄尔的骄傲"  是我
Who used to be the Pride of Lowell? Right here.
现在谁是"洛厄尔的骄傲"  是他
Who's the Pride of Lowell now? Right there.
本来就该是这样
That's how it's meant to be, you know?
把这份骄傲传下去  没什么比这更好了
Hand it down to him. Nothing better than that.
没什么比这更好了
Nothing better than that...
他做到了  我得走了
He did it. I've got to go.
我得走了
I've got to go.
米奇・沃德又和阿图罗・加蒂进行了三场比赛
出场费达到几百万
他在2003年退役
米奇在2005年娶了夏琳  他们和女儿凯茜一起生活在洛厄尔
迪奇依然是当地的传奇人物
他在弟弟的体育馆训练拳击手
呱呱
Quacker!
你的牙怎么没了
Boo, where's your teeth?